<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Defs>
  
	<ThingDef>
		<defName>AE_ForbiddenFruit</defName>
		<label>giant apple</label>
		<description>A normal looking apple, if not for it giant size. Despite its immense size, the apple seems perfectly ripe, its skin giving slightly with the promise of juicy sweetness.\n\nSeems like you can take a bite of it.</description>
		<thingClass>ThingWithComps</thingClass>
		<category>Item</category>
		<genericMarketSellable>false</genericMarketSellable>
		<drawerType>MapMeshOnly</drawerType>
		<tickerType>Normal</tickerType>
		<rotatable>false</rotatable>
		<altitudeLayer>Item</altitudeLayer>
		<selectable>true</selectable>
		<useHitPoints>false</useHitPoints>
		<healthAffectsPrice>false</healthAffectsPrice>
		<alwaysHaulable>true</alwaysHaulable>
		<drawGUIOverlay>true</drawGUIOverlay>
		<pathCost>14</pathCost>
		<graphicData>
			<graphicClass>Graphic_Single</graphicClass>
			<texPath>Things/Item/Special/AE_ForbiddenFruit</texPath>
		</graphicData>
		<statBases>
			<Mass>1</Mass>
			<Beauty>20</Beauty>
			<Flammability>0</Flammability>
			<MarketValue>260</MarketValue>
		</statBases>
		<thingCategories>
			<li>ItemsAnomalies</li>
		</thingCategories>
		<hiddenWhileUndiscovered>true</hiddenWhileUndiscovered>
		<allowedArchonexusCount>1</allowedArchonexusCount>
		<comps>
			<li Class="CompProperties_Interactable">
				<compClass>AnomaliesExpected.Comp_ForbiddenFruit</compClass>
				<activeTicks>1</activeTicks>
				<cooldownTicks>30000</cooldownTicks>
				<ticksToActivate>250</ticksToActivate>
				<activateTexPath>Things/Item/Special/AE_ForbiddenFruit</activateTexPath>
        
				<activateLabelString>Take a bite</activateLabelString>
				<activateDescString>Make someone take a bite of this apple and consume it.</activateDescString>
				<guiLabelString>Choose who should bite this.</guiLabelString>
				<jobString>bite</jobString>
				<activatingStringPending>biting {0}</activatingStringPending>
				<activatingString>biting {0}: {1}s</activatingString>

				<fleckOnUsed>PsycastAreaEffect</fleckOnUsed>
				<fleckOnUsedScale>3</fleckOnUsedScale>
				<soundActivate>PsychicAnimalPulserCast</soundActivate>

				<targetingParameters>
					<canTargetBuildings>false</canTargetBuildings>
					<canTargetAnimals>false</canTargetAnimals>
					<canTargetMechs>false</canTargetMechs>
					<onlyTargetControlledPawns>true</onlyTargetControlledPawns>
				</targetingParameters>
			</li>
			<li Class="CompProperties_Studiable">
				<frequencyTicks>120000</frequencyTicks>
				<knowledgeCategory>Basic</knowledgeCategory>
				<anomalyKnowledge>1</anomalyKnowledge>
				<minMonolithLevelForStudy>1</minMonolithLevelForStudy>
				<showToggleGizmo>true</showToggleGizmo>
			</li>
			<li Class="CompProperties_StudyUnlocks">
				<compClass>AnomaliesExpected.CompAEStudyUnlocks</compClass>
				<studyNotes>
					<li Class="AnomaliesExpected.AEStudyNote">
						<AnomalyLabel>holy apple</AnomalyLabel>
						<AnomalyDesc>A normal looking apple, if not for it giant size. Despite its immense size, the apple seems perfectly ripe, its skin giving slightly with the promise of juicy sweetness.\n\nThe apple regenerates after being bitten, allowing for partial consumption.\n\nClassified as Class-0 (Safe) anomaly.</AnomalyDesc>
						<threshold>0.01</threshold>
						<label>#1/4 Giant apple study report</label>
						<text>Regenerative Properties of a Giant Apple\n\nSubject: {PAWN_nameDef}\n\nAbstract:\nA giant apple exhibited remarkable resilience, resisting damage from blades, fire, and blunt force. Consumption triggered rapid regeneration of bitten pieces and a positive subjective experience in the subject. Further research is needed to explore potential applications and long-term effects of the apple's anomalous properties.\n\nObservations:\nSubject was presented with a standard steel knife. {PAWN_nameDef} attempted to cut apple, but to no avail.\nSubject attempted to smash apple onto solid ground. It remained completely undamaged.\n{PAWN_nameDef} exposed apple to a controlled fire for 30 minutes. Upon extinguishing the fire, the apple exhibited no signs of charring or melting.\nSubject was instructed to bite the apple without swallowing the piece. {PAWN_nameDef} was able to effortlessly bit off a portion of apple and put it next to apple itself. The bitten portion displayed rapid decomposition, while the remaining apple regenerated the missing piece within a short period.\n\nOutcome:\nNo hostile response was observed during interaction.\nAfter experiment {PAWN_nameDef} reported a sensation of "holiness" upon biting the apple.\n\nDiscussion:\nThe giant apple appears indestructible by conventional means.\nThe apple can be bitten and consumed by humans. \nThe apple possesses a regenerative property that activates upon consumption of a portion.\nThe anomalous properties of giant apple have potential applications and risks that need to be explored.\nTemporary giant apple has been classified as Class-0 (Safe) anomaly.\n\nRecommendations:\nFurther experimentation of biting and eating of apple is required to explore effects it have on human body.</text>
					</li>
					<li Class="AnomaliesExpected.AEStudyNote">
						<AnomalyLabel>holy apple</AnomalyLabel>
						<AnomalyDesc>A normal looking apple, if not for it giant size. Despite its immense size, the apple seems perfectly ripe, its skin giving slightly with the promise of juicy sweetness.\n\nThe apple regenerates after being bitten, allowing for partial consumption. Which increases the speed of learning and knowledge acquisition by the consumer.\n\nClassified as Class-0 (Safe) anomaly.</AnomalyDesc>
						<threshold>2</threshold>
						<label>#2/4 Giant apple study report</label>
						<text>Enhanced Learning and Divine Inspiration\n\nSubject: [REDACTED]\n\nAbstract:\nConsumption of a giant anomalous apple led to a drastic increase in learning speed and knowledge retention in the Subject. The Subject reported experiencing divine inspiration and a heightened understanding of a divine entity. Further research is needed to understand the source of the knowledge and potential long-term effects.\n\nObservations:\nSubject was instructed to bite the apple and swallow the piece. After consumption, [REDACTED] reported experiencing a surge of divine inspiration, accompanied by a newfound sense of wisdom. Notably, the Subject achieved a breakthrough on a previously encountered task that had posed an initial challenge.\nSubject was then instructed to consume another bite of the apple. [REDACTED] reported a further increase in their understanding of the divine will.\n\nOutcome:\nSubject demonstrated a significant improvement in knowledge retention and learning speed compared to pre-experiment baseline.\n[REDACTED] described gaining access to previously unconsidered perspectives and experiencing a heightened sense of connection to a divine entity.\n\nDiscussion:\nThese findings suggest that consumption of the anomalous apple facilitates accelerated learning and knowledge acquisition in the subject. The rate of learning appears to correlate with the amount of apple consumed. \nFurther investigation is required to determine the source of this knowledge and the potential long-term effects of repeated exposure.\n\nRecommendations:\nContinued experimentation with controlled apple consumption is necessary to fully understand the cognitive effects on the subject. Monitoring of the subject's health and mental state is crucial throughout the research process.</text>
					</li>
					<li Class="AnomaliesExpected.AEStudyNote">
						<AnomalyLabel>the forbidden fruit of knowledge</AnomalyLabel>
						<AnomalyDesc>A normal looking apple, if not for it giant size. Despite its immense size, the apple seems perfectly ripe, its skin giving slightly with the promise of juicy sweetness.\n\nThe apple regenerates after being bitten, allowing for partial consumption. Which increases the speed of learning and knowledge acquisition by the consumer. Long term consumption can anger the divine entity, leading to the death of consumer.\n\nClassified as Class-1 (Caution) anomaly.</AnomalyDesc>
						<threshold>3</threshold>
						<label>#3/4 Giant apple study report</label>
						<text>The Forbidden Fruit of Knowledge\n\nSubject: [REDACTED]\n\nAbstract:\nFurther consumption of the anomalous apple yielded greater knowledge, but triggered fear and connection to an angered divine entity perceiving the fruit as forbidden. The subject fainted and reported about potential death from continuation of consumption. The experiment highlights long-term risks and necessitates an inhibitor serum to counter the connection. The anomaly has been reclassified as Class-1 (Caution).\n\nObservations:\nFollowing previous successful trials with partial apple consumption, Subject was instructed to repeat the procedure. [REDACTED] reported a significantly larger influx of knowledge compared to prior experiences. However, Subject also exhibited signs of mild dizziness and expressed a troubling feeling that the acquired knowledge was not meant for them.\nFurther consumption of the apple resulted in a partial loss of consciousness and fear in Subject. [REDACTED] reported establishing a partial connection with a divine entity, who expressed anger at their consumption of The Forbidden Fruit. Subject displayed agitation, screaming about never touching the fruit again and pleading for forgiveness.\n\nOutcome:\n[REDACTED] experienced significant stress and subsequently fainted.\nUpon regaining consciousness, Subject explained that he was able to partially understand the divine entity and its anger regarding the consumption of the forbidden fruit, which was not meant for humans. [REDACTED] further reported that continued interaction with the fruit during this entity's Wrath could result in their death.\n\nDiscussion:\nThis experiment highlights the potential risks associated with long-term exposure to the apple's effects.\nNotably, one researcher proposed the development of an inhibitor serum to potentially counter the subject's connection with the divine entity.\nReclassified holy apple of knowledge as Class-1 (Caution) anomaly, due to reaction and information from [REDACTED].\n\nRecommendations:\nFurther experimentation with the proposed inhibitor serum is necessary to assess its effectiveness in mitigating the negative effects of the apple.</text>
					</li>
					<li Class="AnomaliesExpected.AEStudyNote">
						<AnomalyLabel>the forbidden fruit of knowledge</AnomalyLabel>
						<AnomalyDesc>A normal looking apple, if not for it giant size. Despite its immense size, the apple seems perfectly ripe, its skin giving slightly with the promise of juicy sweetness. It consumtion allow consciousness connection with a higher dimensional being.\n\nThe apple regenerates after being bitten, allowing for partial consumption. Which increases the speed of learning and knowledge acquisition by the consumer. Long term consumption can anger the divine entity, leading to the death of consumer.\n\nClassified as Class-1 (Caution) anomaly.</AnomalyDesc>
						<threshold>5</threshold>
						<label>#4/4 Giant apple study report</label>
						<text>Theory Regarding Giant Apple\n\nSubject: [REDACTED]\n\nAbstract:\nInhibitor serum successfully severed the connection between a [REDACTED] and a higher-dimensional entity triggered by consuming a forbidden knowledge fruit. The disconnection caused a temporary learning speed decline but no lasting harm. Subject theorizes the fruit originates from the entity's garden and facilitates knowledge exchange. The entity fears humanity reaching its level and hinders excessive knowledge gain. Removal or controlled use with safety protocols are recommended for the giant apple.\n\nObservations:\nSubject was instructed to inject giant apple inhibitor serum during divine entity's Wrath period. Following the injection, [REDACTED] reported a significant decrease in stress levels and a diminished ability to perceive the entity's voice. Subject further described a general sense of improvement. \nAfter several days, [REDACTED] confirmed a complete severance of the connection with the divine entity.\n\nOutcome:\nGiant apple inhibitor serum successfully severed Subject's connection with the divine entity. \nHowever, Subject also experienced a temporary decline in learning speed over the course of the observation period.\n\nHypothesis:\nBased on the overall experience, [REDACTED] proposes a theory regarding the origin of The Forbidden Fruit of Knowledge. Subject suggests that the fruit originates from a garden controlled by the encountered divine entity. Consumption of the fruit establishes a connection between the consumer's consciousness and the entity, facilitating the exchange of knowledge and thoughts. [REDACTED] further hypothesizes that the divine entity, existing in a higher dimension, possesses the capability to observe and potentially influence our facility on a level not accessible to humans. The appearance of the fruit outside our facility is attributed to interdimensional travel. While the entity seems indifferent to lower levels of knowledge access, it fears the potential of humanity achieving its level of understanding. This fear manifests as attempts to hinder excessive knowledge acquisition through the fruit. Disconnecting from the entity's mind via the serum injection allows it to gradually forget about our existence, similar to how a human might forget an insignificant ant encountered in an anthill.\n\nDiscussion:\nThe severance of the connection with the entity through the serum requires time and comes with a temporary learning speed penalty. However, post-disconnection observations indicate no lasting negative effects for the subject.\n\nRecommendations:\nRemoval: Given the potential for accidental death due to excessive consumption, it removal from facility may be the most prudent course of action.\nControlled Use: Alternatively, if hypothesis is right, then continued use of giant apple, under controlled and monitored conditions, could offer substantial benefits in terms of learning and knowledge acquisition. This approach, however, necessitates thorough risk assessment and the development of safety protocols to safeguard colonists' well-being.</text>
					</li>
				</studyNotes>
			</li>
			<li Class="CompProperties_Forbiddable"/>
		</comps>
		<inspectorTabs>
			<li>ITab_StudyNotes</li>
		</inspectorTabs>
	</ThingDef>
	
	<ThingDef>
		<defName>AE_DogTag</defName>
		<label>Ripped off dog tag</label>
		<description>A tiny plasteel tag, bearing basic details about an individual, typically used to identify casualties.\n\nIt's been torn off, and the name on it seems familiar to you. Maybe someone can interact with it.</description>
		<thingClass>ThingWithComps</thingClass>
		<graphicData>
			<graphicClass>Graphic_Single</graphicClass>
			<texPath>Things/Item/Special/AE_AnomalyDogTag</texPath>
			<onGroundRandomRotateAngle>35</onGroundRandomRotateAngle>
			<drawSize>(0.75,0.75)</drawSize>
		</graphicData>
		<category>Item</category>
		<genericMarketSellable>false</genericMarketSellable>
		<drawerType>MapMeshOnly</drawerType>
		<tickerType>Never</tickerType>
		<rotatable>true</rotatable>
		<altitudeLayer>Item</altitudeLayer>
		<selectable>true</selectable>
		<useHitPoints>false</useHitPoints>
		<healthAffectsPrice>false</healthAffectsPrice>
		<alwaysHaulable>true</alwaysHaulable>
		<drawGUIOverlay>true</drawGUIOverlay>
		<pathCost>1</pathCost>
		<statBases>
			<Mass>1</Mass>
			<Beauty>10</Beauty>
			<Flammability>0</Flammability>
			<MarketValue>5</MarketValue>
		</statBases>
		<thingCategories>
			<li>ItemsMisc</li>
		</thingCategories>
		<comps>
			<li Class="AnomaliesExpected.CompProperties_DogTag">
				<activeTicks>1</activeTicks>
				<ticksToActivate>250</ticksToActivate>
				<activateTexPath>Things/Item/Special/AE_AnomalyDogTag</activateTexPath>
        
				<activateLabelString>Touch</activateLabelString>
				<activateDescString>Make someone touch the dog tag.</activateDescString>
				<guiLabelString>Choose who should touch this.</guiLabelString>
				<jobString>touch</jobString>
				<activatingStringPending>touching {0}</activatingStringPending>
				<activatingString>touching {0}: {1}s</activatingString>

				<fleckOnUsed>PsycastAreaEffect</fleckOnUsed>
				<fleckOnUsedScale>1</fleckOnUsedScale>
				<soundActivate>PsychicAnimalPulserCast</soundActivate>

				<targetingParameters>
					<canTargetBuildings>false</canTargetBuildings>
					<canTargetAnimals>false</canTargetAnimals>
					<canTargetMechs>false</canTargetMechs>
					<onlyTargetControlledPawns>true</onlyTargetControlledPawns>
				</targetingParameters>
				
				<hediffOnUse>Hediff_AEDogTag</hediffOnUse>
				<chanceToCensor>0.5</chanceToCensor>
				<symbolsToCensor>/|\—</symbolsToCensor>
			</li>
		</comps>
	</ThingDef>
  
</Defs>