<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Defs>

	<ThingDef ParentName="Bed">
		<defName>AE_AnomalyBed</defName>
		<label>ordinary bed</label>
		<description>A cozy mattress and sheets on a frame made of organic metal for resting.\n\nSeems like the only way to understand it more is for someone to sleep on it.</description>
		<thingClass>AnomaliesExpected.Building_AEBed</thingClass>
		<graphicData>
			<texPath>Things/Building/AE_AnomalyBed</texPath>
			<graphicClass>Graphic_Multi</graphicClass>
			<shaderType>CutoutComplex</shaderType>
			<drawSize>(2,2)</drawSize>
			<damageData>
				<rect>(0,0.05,1,1.95)</rect>
			</damageData>
		</graphicData>
		<statBases>
			<Beauty>1</Beauty>
			<BedRestEffectiveness>0.25</BedRestEffectiveness>
			<Comfort>0.25</Comfort>
		</statBases>
		<stuffCategories Inherit="False"/>
		<costStuffCount/>
		<costList>
			<Bioferrite>45</Bioferrite>
		</costList>
		<tickerType>Rare</tickerType>
		<designationCategory/>
		<comps>
			<li Class="AnomaliesExpected.CompProperties_AnomalyBed"/>
			<li Class="CompProperties_Studiable">
				<compClass>AnomaliesExpected.CompStudiableAE</compClass>
				<frequencyTicks>120000</frequencyTicks>
				<knowledgeCategory>Basic</knowledgeCategory>
				<knowledgeFactorOutdoors>0</knowledgeFactorOutdoors>
				<anomalyKnowledge>0</anomalyKnowledge>
				<minMonolithLevelForStudy>1</minMonolithLevelForStudy>
				<studyEnabledByDefault>false</studyEnabledByDefault>
			</li>
			<li Class="CompProperties_StudyUnlocks">
				<compClass>AnomaliesExpected.CompAEStudyUnlocks</compClass>
				<studyNotes>
					<li Class="AnomaliesExpected.AEStudyNote">
						<AnomalyLabel>anomalous bed</AnomalyLabel>
						<AnomalyDesc>A cozy mattress and sheets on a frame made of organic metal for resting. A colonist sleeping on this bed will rest abnormally quickly.\n\nProviding study knowledge about anomaly when someone sleep on it.\n\nClassified as Class-0 (Safe) anomaly.</AnomalyDesc>
						<threshold>1</threshold>
						<label>#1/3 Ordinary bed study report</label>
						<text>Enhanced Cognitive Function Following Non-Standard Sleep\n\nSubject: {PAWN_nameDef}\n\nAbstract:\nThis report details observations of Subject {PAWN_nameDef} following a period of sleep on ordinary bed. This deviated from the typical sleep protocol within the facility. While Subject exhibited abnormally rapid sleep and atypical brain activity, no adverse effects were noted. Interestingly, upon awakening, {PAWN_nameDef} reported newfound knowledge directly related to ongoing anomalies research in the facility. This information appears unrelated to prior exposure within the facility, suggesting unconventional pathways to data acquisition. Current research protocols may not be optimally suited to study this phenomenon. Further investigation is warranted.\n\nObservations:\n{PAWN_nameDef} was permitted to utilize ordinary bed for sleep, deviating from the standard protocol.\nSleep duration was significantly shorter than the norm for Subject.\nBrainwave patterns deviated from baseline readings during sleep.\nNo negative physical or behavioral changes were observed post-sleep.\n\nOutcome:\nUpon awakening, {PAWN_nameDef} reported novel information relevant to ongoing research on anomalies in the facility.\nThe reported information was not previously known to Subject and could not be attributed to standard briefings or exposure within the facility.\n\nDiscussion:\nThese findings suggest a potential correlation between non-standard sleep and enhanced cognitive function, specifically related to anomaly research. Conventional research methods may not be sufficient to explore this phenomenon.\nTemporary anomalous bed has been classified as Class-0 (Safe) anomaly.\n\nRecommendations:\nFurther experimentation is required to substantiate these observations.  Additional tests with {PAWN_nameDef} and potentially other subjects are recommended to explore the potential of non-standard sleep and acquisition of research-relevant data.</text>
					</li>
					<li Class="AnomaliesExpected.AEStudyNote">
						<AnomalyLabel>anomalous bed</AnomalyLabel>
						<AnomalyDesc>A cozy mattress and sheets on a frame made of organic metal for resting. A colonist sleeping on this bed will rest abnormally quickly. Resting in the anomalous bed appears to be linked to fatigue of colonists who haven't used them.\n\nProviding study knowledge about anomaly when someone sleep on it.\n\nClassified as Class-0 (Safe) anomaly.</AnomalyDesc>
						<threshold>7</threshold>
						<label>#2/3 Ordinary bed study report</label>
						<text>Potential Correlation with Fatigue of Colonists\n\nAbstract:\nThis report details observations concerning the effects of ordinary bed introduced into a research facility housing colonists. Following its arrival, a significant portion of the colonists exhibited increased fatigue. Notably, the severity of fatigue appeared to correlate directly with the frequency of experiments conducted utilizing the ordinary bed. These findings suggest a potential link between the ordinary bed and colonists well-being. Given this observation, continued experimentation with the ordinary bed is recommended with caution. Further investigation into the bed's properties and its impact on colonists' physiology is warranted.\n\nObservations:\nFollowing the introduction of ordinary bed into the facility, a notable increase in fatigue was observed amongst several colonists.\nThe severity of fatigue appears to be directly proportional to the number of experiments conducted utilizing the ordinary bed.\n\nDiscussion:\nThese findings suggest a potential link between the ordinary bed and the colonists fatigue. The observed correlation between experiment frequency and fatigue intensity warrants further investigation.\n\nConsiderations:\nThe data aligns with previous observations regarding Subject's abnormal sleep on ordinary bed. Both instances deviate from the established rest protocols and suggest potential unforeseen consequences associated with standard sleep environments within the facility.\n\nRecommendations:\nGiven the potential detrimental effects, continued experimentation with the ordinary bed should be undertaken with caution. Further analysis of the ordinary bed's properties and its impact on colonists physiology is recommended.</text>
					</li>
					<li Class="AnomaliesExpected.AEStudyNote">
						<AnomalyLabel>neural collective processing unit</AnomalyLabel>
						<AnomalyDesc>A cozy mattress and sheets on a frame made of organic metal for resting. A neural processor hidden within itself that utilizes the brain neurons of people in its vicinity, helping to increase information processing capacity within the sleeper. A colonist sleeping on this bed will rest abnormally quickly, while draining rest of other colonists in the facility and causing fatigue on them.\n\nProviding study knowledge about anomalies research in the facility proportional to the amount of rest restored.\n\nClassified as Class-0 (Safe) anomaly.</AnomalyDesc>
						<threshold>15</threshold>
						<label>#3/3 Ordinary bed study report</label>
						<text>Theory Regarding Ordinary Bed and Enhanced Cognitive Function\n\nSubject: {PAWN_nameDef}\n\nAbstract:\nThis report presents a novel theory proposed by Subject {PAWN_nameDef} regarding ordinary bed introduced into a research facility. Subject suggests the bed interacts with the brain neurons of nearby colonists, facilitating enhanced information processing capacity within the sleeper and leading to faster sleep recovery. This theory is based on data obtained during an anomalous sleep event involving Subject and ordinary bed. As a result of this event, the anomaly associated with the bed has been classified as Safe. Report concludes by outlining two primary options for moving forward: termination of the experiment by destruction of the ordinary bed, or continued use under controlled conditions for potential gain of research information.\n\nHypothesis:\nFollowing their non-standard sleep experience, {PAWN_nameDef} has proposed a theory concerning the ordinary bed. Subject suggest the bed utilizes the brain neurons of colonists in its vicinity. This interaction, according to {PAWN_nameDef}, facilitates increased information processing capacity within the sleeper.\n\nDiscussion:\n{PAWN_nameDef}'s theory posits that by leveraging the colonists' collective neural network, the ordinary bed reduces the cognitive load on the sleeper's individual brain. This, in turn, would explain the observed rapid sleep recovery in Subject's case.\nBased on information gleaned during this anomalous sleep event, {PAWN_nameDef} has successfully classified the anomaly associated with the ordinary bed as Class-0 (Safe) anomaly.\n\nConsiderations:\nThe potential validity of Subject's theory requires further investigation. Additionally, a critical decision must be made regarding the ordinary bed. Reclassification not required.\n\nRecommendations:\nDestruction: Given the potential for unforeseen consequences related to the standard bed's influence on colonists' neural activity, its destruction may be the most prudent course of action.\nControlled Use: Alternatively, if Subject's theory regarding information processing holds merit, continued use of the standard bed, under controlled and monitored conditions, could offer significant advantages in anomaly research. This approach, however, necessitates thorough risk assessment and the development of safety protocols to safeguard colonists' well-being.</text>
					</li>
				</studyNotes>
			</li>
		</comps>
		<inspectorTabs>
			<li>ITab_StudyNotes</li>
		</inspectorTabs>
	</ThingDef>
	
	<ThingDef ParentName="BedWithQualityBase">
		<defName>AE_AnomalyHospitalBed</defName>
		<label>ordinary hospital bed</label>
		<description>A bed with a frame made of organic metal specially designed for use in hospitals. Adjustable for a patient and festooned with built-in equipment, it improves medical outcomes over normal beds. Medical clipboard lying on the bed with some text written on it.\n\nSeems like the only way to understand it more is for someone who require medical assistance to be put on it.</description>
		<thingClass>AnomaliesExpected.Building_AEBed</thingClass>
		<graphicData>
			<texPath>Things/Building/AE_AnomalyHospitalBed</texPath>
			<graphicClass>Graphic_Multi</graphicClass>
			<shaderType>CutoutComplex</shaderType>
			<drawSize>(2,2)</drawSize>
			<damageData>
				<rect>(0,0.05,1,1.95)</rect>
			</damageData>
		</graphicData>
		<castEdgeShadows>True</castEdgeShadows>
		<size>(1,2)</size>
		<statBases>
			<Beauty>1</Beauty>
			<MaxHitPoints>150</MaxHitPoints>
			<Mass>35</Mass>
			<Flammability>1.0</Flammability>
			<BedRestEffectiveness>0.25</BedRestEffectiveness>
			<Comfort>0.25</Comfort>
			<ImmunityGainSpeedFactor>1.2</ImmunityGainSpeedFactor>
			<MedicalTendQualityOffset>0.15</MedicalTendQualityOffset>
			<SurgerySuccessChanceFactor>1.2</SurgerySuccessChanceFactor>
			<BirthRitualQualityOffset MayRequire="Ludeon.RimWorld.Biotech">10</BirthRitualQualityOffset>
		</statBases>
		<costList>
			<Bioferrite>120</Bioferrite>
			<ComponentIndustrial>5</ComponentIndustrial>
		</costList>
		<building>
			<bed_showSleeperBody>False</bed_showSleeperBody>
			<bed_healPerDay>10</bed_healPerDay>
			<bed_defaultMedical>true</bed_defaultMedical>
			<buildingSizeCategory>Small</buildingSizeCategory>
			<paintable>true</paintable>
		</building>
		<fillPercent>0.4</fillPercent>
		<pathCost>42</pathCost>
		<leaveResourcesWhenKilled>True</leaveResourcesWhenKilled>
		<staticSunShadowHeight>0.17</staticSunShadowHeight>
		<designationCategory/>
		<uiIconScale>0.90</uiIconScale>
		<comps>
			<li Class="AnomaliesExpected.CompProperties_AnomalyHospitalBed">
				<ClipboardSize>5</ClipboardSize>
				<MaxMissed>10</MaxMissed>
				<ticksPerSign>10000</ticksPerSign>
				<TendQuality>1</TendQuality>
				<MaxDamage>5</MaxDamage>
				<MultInjury>1</MultInjury>
				<MultInfection>100</MultInfection>
				<MultBloodLoss>50</MultBloodLoss>
				<StudyHealMult>0.005</StudyHealMult>
				<StudyConsumeMult>0.015</StudyConsumeMult>
				<SeverityPerDmgDonorMult>0.5</SeverityPerDmgDonorMult>
			</li>
			<li Class="CompProperties_Studiable">
				<compClass>AnomaliesExpected.CompStudiableAE</compClass>
				<frequencyTicks>120000</frequencyTicks>
				<knowledgeCategory>Advanced</knowledgeCategory>
				<knowledgeFactorOutdoors>0</knowledgeFactorOutdoors>
				<anomalyKnowledge>0</anomalyKnowledge>
				<minMonolithLevelForStudy>1</minMonolithLevelForStudy>
				<studyEnabledByDefault>false</studyEnabledByDefault>
			</li>
			<li Class="CompProperties_StudyUnlocks">
				<compClass>AnomaliesExpected.CompAEStudyUnlocks</compClass>
				<studyNotes>
					<li Class="AnomaliesExpected.AEStudyNote">
						<AnomalyLabel>anomalous hospital bed</AnomalyLabel>
						<AnomalyDesc>A bed with a frame made of organic metal specially designed for use in hospitals. Adjustable for a patient and festooned with built-in equipment, it improves medical outcomes over normal beds. Medical clipboard lying on the bed with some text written on it. An injured colonist lying on it will heal abnormaly fast.\n\nProviding study knowledge about anomaly when someone who require medical assistance to be put on it.\n\nClassified as Class-0 (Safe) anomaly.</AnomalyDesc>
						<threshold>0.01</threshold>
						<label>#1/5 Ordinary hospital bed study report</label>
						<text>Anomalous Hospital Bed Demonstrates Rapid Regeneration\n\nSubject: {PAWN_nameDef}\n\nAbstract:\nAnomalous healing properties were observed during initial testing of a recovered hospital bed. Upon Subject entry, a crimson fluid emerged from the bed frame, engulfing the Subject. Following absorption of the fluid back to frame, all prior injuries were healed at an accelerated rate. The bed generated a new data entry on an accompanying it medical clipboard. These findings suggest the potential of the bed as a valuable medical resource. Further experimentation is required to understand the phenomenon and solidify these initial observations.\n\nObservations:\nNothing written on medical clipboard.\nSubject requires some medical assistance.\n{PAWN_nameDef} instructed to lie down on a hospital bed.\nAfter short time a crimson fluid emerged from the bed frame, engulfing the Subject entirely.\nSubject's stress levels exhibited a minor increase.\nFollowing another brief interval, the fluid was entirely absorbed back into the bed frame, uncovering Subject.\n{PAWN_nameDef} was able to stand up from the bed by themself.\nSome text appeared on on the previously blank medical clipboard.\n\nOutcome:\nAll prior injuries sustained by the Subject healed at an anomalous rate.\n{PAWN_nameDef} was happy regarding the swift and painless recovery process.\nTextual data subsequently appeared on medical clipboard as one new row on it with information about {PAWN_nameDef}, it injuries that was healed and some score next to it.\nSome study knowledge was produced during this experiment.\n\nDiscussion:\nThis positive result showed that this hospital bed have potential as a valuable medical resource for this facility.\nConventional research methods may not be sufficient to explore this phenomenon.\nTemporary anomalous hospital bed has been classified as Class-0 (Safe) anomaly.\n\nRecommendations:\nFurther experimentation utilizing subjects with varying degrees of injury is necessary to solidify these findings.</text>
					</li>
					<li Class="AnomaliesExpected.AEStudyNote">
						<AnomalyLabel>anomalous hospital bed</AnomalyLabel>
						<AnomalyDesc>A bed with a frame made of organic metal specially designed for use in hospitals. Adjustable for a patient and festooned with built-in equipment, it improves medical outcomes over normal beds. Medical clipboard lying on the bed with some text written on it. An injured colonist lying on it will heal abnormaly fast, but in some cases will get more injuries.\n\nProviding study knowledge about anomaly when someone who require medical assistance to be put on it.\n\nClassified as Class-1 (Caution) anomaly.</AnomalyDesc>
						<threshold>4</threshold>
						<label>#2/5 Ordinary hospital bed study report</label>
						<text>Unexpected Shift in Anomalous Healing Properties\n\nSubject: [REDACTED]\n\nAbstract:\nInitial success with an anomalous hospital bed showcasing rapid healing turned problematic in a follow-up experiment. Subject immersion in the crimson fluid, previously observed to heal injuries, resulted in no positive change and instead inflicted new minor wounds. The bed's accompanying medical clipboard displayed altered data.  While further knowledge was gained regarding the anomaly, this unexpected outcome necessitates a reevaluation of its functionality and a heightened safety protocol. The anomalous hospital bed has been reclassified as a Class-1 (Caution) anomaly due to its potential to inflict harm. Further experimentation is crucial to understand the cause of this shift in behavior.\n\nObservations:\nOne row was filled with small score on a medical clipboard.\nSubject requires some medical assistance.\n[REDACTED] instructed to lie down on a hospital bed.\nAfter short time a crimson fluid emerged from the bed frame, engulfing the Subject entirely.\nSubject's stress levels increased.\nFollowing another brief interval, the fluid was entirely absorbed back into the bed frame, uncovering Subject.\n[REDACTED] displayed signs of panic and examined its body.\nText changed on a medical clipboard.\n\nOutcome:\nAll previously documented injuries of the Subject remained unhealed.\n[REDACTED] manifested new superficial cuts and minor injuries on its body.\nRow with a score dissapeared on a medical clipboard. No additional row about [REDACTED] wasn't added.\nStudy knowledge was produced during this experiment surpassing that of the previous experiment.\n\nDiscussion:\nThe unexpected results of this experiment necessitate reevaluation of our understanding of this anomaly.\nReclassified anomalous hospital bed as Class-1 (Caution) anomaly.\n\nConsiderations:\nIt is crucial to note that the anomaly, unlike previously observed behavior, now demonstrates the potential to inflict harm. This poses a significant threat to the safety of colonists.\n\nRecommendations:\nGiven the potential detrimental effects, continued experimentation with the hospital bed should be undertaken with caution. \nFurther experimentation with injured subjects is required to determine the cause of such change of behaviour.</text>
					</li>
					<li Class="AnomaliesExpected.AEStudyNote">
						<AnomalyLabel>anomalous hospital bed</AnomalyLabel>
						<AnomalyDesc>A bed with a frame made of organic metal specially designed for use in hospitals. Adjustable for a patient and festooned with built-in equipment, it improves medical outcomes over normal beds. Medical clipboard lying on the bed with some text written on it. An injured colonist lying on it will heal abnormaly fast, but in some cases will get more injuries or can lead to colonist death.\n\nProviding study knowledge about anomaly when someone who require medical assistance to be put on it.\n\nClassified as Class-2 (Warning) anomaly.</AnomalyDesc>
						<threshold>9</threshold>
						<label>#3/5 Ordinary hospital bed study report</label>
						<text>Anomalous Bed Reveals Lethal Potential\n\nSubject: [REDACTED]\n\nAbstract:\nA seemingly healthy [REDACTED] subjected to an anomalous hospital bed resulted in a catastrophic outcome. The hospital bed, previously exhibiting regenerative properties, inflicted significant injuries and tissue loss on the Subject, leading to its demise. The accompanying medical clipboard displayed a decrease in previously high scores, suggesting a potential correlation with the subject's outcome. Experiment highlighted the unpredictable and potentially lethal nature of the anomaly. The hospital bed has been reclassified as a Class-2 (Warning) anomaly. Further experimentation, prioritizing subject safety, is crucial to understand the factors influencing this erratic behavior. Notably, this trial demonstrates the potential use of healthy subjects in future research.\n\nObservations:\nFew rows was filled with big score on a medical clipboard.\nSubject didn't required medical assistance.\n[REDACTED] instructed to lie down on a hospital bed.\nAfter short time a crimson fluid emerged from the bed frame, engulfing the Subject entirely.\nSubject's stress levels escalated rapidly, culminating in audible screams.\nAfter screams stopped, the fluid was entirely absorbed back into the bed frame, uncovering Subject, or rather, what remained.\nTextual data on the medical clipboard changed.\n\nOutcome:\n[REDACTED] manifested significant new injuries and substantial tissue loss.\nSubject [REDACTED] expired due to extensive injuries.\nSeveral high-scoring entries on the medical clipboard disappeared. Remaining entries displayed a decrease in score. No new entry for Subject [REDACTED] was generated.\nStudy knowledge was produced during this experiment surpassing that of the first experiment.\n\nDiscussion:\nThe outcome of this experiment has left researchers profoundly disturbed.\nThis experiment also shows that use of healthy subjects is possible.\nReclassified anomalous hospital bed as Class-2 (Warning) anomaly, due to its demonstrated lethality.\n\nRecommendations:\nFurther experimentation with injured subjects is imperative to establish the factors influencing such erratic behavior.</text>
					</li>
					<li Class="AnomaliesExpected.AEStudyNote">
						<AnomalyLabel>anomalous hospital bed</AnomalyLabel>
						<AnomalyDesc>A bed with a frame made of organic metal specially designed for use in hospitals. Adjustable for a patient and festooned with built-in equipment, it improves medical outcomes over normal beds. Medical clipboard lying on the bed with text written on it related to chance of healing/injuring colonist. An injured colonist lying on it will heal abnormaly fast or will get more injuries, which can lead to it death.\n\nProviding study knowledge about anomaly when someone who require medical assistance to be put on it.\n\nClassified as Class-2 (Warning) anomaly.</AnomalyDesc>
						<threshold>15</threshold>
						<label>#4/5 Ordinary hospital bed study report</label>
						<text>Anomalous Medical Bed and Clipboard Reveal Interconnected Nature\n\nAbstract:\nThe anomalous hospital bed exhibits a peculiar connection to its accompanying medical clipboard. Attempts to remove the clipboard resulted in its transformation into a liquid and subsequent reintegration with the bed frame. A new clipboard then materialized, replicating the previous one's data. Analysis of past observations suggests the clipboard acts as a log of interactions with the medical bed. New entries appear upon successful healing (accompanied by a score), while filled rows seem to increase the risk of subject injury, with the severity potentially linked to the total score. This revelation emphasizes the importance of scrutinizing the clipboard's information before using the anomalous hospital bed to enhance safety and potentially unlock the key to understanding of its operation.\n\nObservations:\nAn attempt was made to remove the medical clipboard from the bed.\nUpon moving the clipboard more than one meter away from the bed, it transformed into a liquid state and flowed back onto the hospital bed frame.\nMoments later, a new medical clipboard solidified on top of the bed.\n\nOutcome:\nRemoval of the medical clipboard was unsuccessful.\nThe newly formed clipboard displayed a copy of the previous clipboard's data.\n\nDiscussion:\nConsidering all previous changes in text on a medical clipboard it should be safe to assume that it provides information related to operation that will happen with subject on a medical bed.\nWhen a subject is successfully healed, a new row appears on the clipboard with a corresponding score. This score likely reflects the amount of regeneration that occurred.\nConversely, when rows on the clipboard are not empty, there is a possibility of the subject sustaining injuries. The severity of these injuries seems to correlate with the sum of the scores on the clipboard.\n\nConsiderations:\nAn observer has identified a potential pattern: the likelihood of a subject experiencing injury from the hospital bed appears to be directly related to the percentage of filled rows on the medical clipboard.\n\nRecommendations:\nIt is imperative to pay close attention to the information displayed on the medical clipboard before utilizing the medical bed on a subject. This information may hold the key to safely operating the anomaly.</text>
					</li>
					<li Class="AnomaliesExpected.AEStudyNote">
						<AnomalyLabel>emergency cellular restoration unit</AnomalyLabel>
						<AnomalyDesc>A bed with a frame made of organic metal specially designed for use in hospitals. Have installed crimson liquid tank inside for rapid regeneration inside it fram. Medical clipboard lying on the bed with text written on it related to chance of healing/consuming colonist. An injured colonist lying on it will be healed abnormaly fast or will get consumed for liquid production by dealing more injuries, which can lead to it death.\n\nProviding study knowledge about anomaly when someone who require medical assistance to be put on it.\n\nClassified as Class-2 (Warning) anomaly.</AnomalyDesc>
						<threshold>22</threshold>
						<label>#5/5 Ordinary hospital bed study report</label>
						<text>Theory Regarding Anomalous Medical Bed\n\nAbstract:\nThis report presents a novel theory proposed by one of observers of anomalous medical bed regarding it functionality. Anomaly was labeled as Emergency Cellular Restoration Unit (ECRU). It suggested that ECRU function by utilizing a regenerative crimson liquid stored within its frame. Analysis suggests this liquid repairs human tissue, but requires refilling. The accompanying clipboard may track depletion and indicate refill urgency. A disturbing theory proposes the ECRU consumes tissues of some subject's for refilling, potentially fatally. Research aims to replicate the liquid for safer medical use. The report recommends either destroying the ECRU or implementing strict protocols for controlled use.\n\nHypothesis:\nAn observer, drawing upon observations from all experiments and information gleaned from surviving subjects, has proposed a theory concerning the Emergency Cellular Restoration Unit functionality. The ECRU frame likely houses a reservoir containing a regenerative crimson liquid that stimulates human tissue repair. The accompanying medical clipboard potentially tracks the liquid's depletion and indicates the urgency of refilling. When a refill is necessary, next subject's tissues will be consumed to produce liquid. The outcome for the subject depends on the volume required, with a potential risk of fatality. A portion of the liquid might be used to maintain the functionality of the organic metal frame.\n\nDiscussion:\nWe might be able to use this knowledge to replicate production of this liquid of lower concentration for usage between colonists.\nAnomalous medical bed was renamed to Emergency Cellular Restoration Unit.\n\nRecommendations:\nDestruction: Given the potential for accidental death on this medical bed, its destruction may be the most prudent course of action.\nControlled Use: Alternatively, if hypothesis is right, then continued use of ECRU, under controlled and monitored conditions, could offer significant advantages in medical care. This approach, however, necessitates thorough risk assessment and the development of safety protocols to safeguard colonists' well-being.</text>
					</li>
				</studyNotes>
			</li>
			<li Class="CompProperties_AffectedByFacilities">
				<linkableFacilities>
					<li>VitalsMonitor</li>
					<li>EndTable</li>
					<li>Dresser</li>
					<li MayRequire="Ludeon.RimWorld.Ideology">SleepAccelerator</li>
				</linkableFacilities>
			</li>
		</comps>
		<inspectorTabs>
			<li>ITab_StudyNotes</li>
		</inspectorTabs>
	</ThingDef>
	
	<ThingDef ParentName="BuildingBase">
		<defName>AE_MeatGrinder</defName>
		<label>industrial metal box</label>
		<description>This industrial-looking metal box as tall as a table. Several small doors interrupt the smooth surface on its sides, while a big hole with hidden inside blades sits atop it. A lone button rests next to the hole, hinting at some unknown function.</description>
		<thingClass>AnomaliesExpected.Building_AE</thingClass>
		<graphicData>
			<texPath>Things/Building/AE_MeatGrinder</texPath>
			<graphicClass>Graphic_Single</graphicClass>
			<drawSize>(2.76,2.76)</drawSize>
		</graphicData>
		<size>(1,1)</size>
		<uiIconScale>0.75</uiIconScale>
		<canOverlapZones>false</canOverlapZones>
		<minifiedDef>MinifiedThing</minifiedDef>
		<thingCategories>
			<li>BuildingsFurniture</li>
		</thingCategories>
		<terrainAffordanceNeeded>Medium</terrainAffordanceNeeded>
		<altitudeLayer>Building</altitudeLayer>
		<castEdgeShadows>true</castEdgeShadows>
		<staticSunShadowHeight>0.20</staticSunShadowHeight>
		<costList>
			<Bioferrite>45</Bioferrite>
		</costList>
		<fillPercent>0.5</fillPercent>
		<useHitPoints>True</useHitPoints>
		<statBases>
			<Mass>20</Mass>
			<WorkToBuild>2000</WorkToBuild>
			<MaxHitPoints>180</MaxHitPoints>
			<Flammability>0</Flammability>
			<Cleanliness>-30</Cleanliness>
		</statBases>
		<passability>PassThroughOnly</passability>
		<pathCost>50</pathCost>
		<surfaceType>Item</surfaceType>
		<tickerType>Normal</tickerType>
		<designationCategory/>
		<killedLeavings>
			<AEGrinderJaw>1</AEGrinderJaw>
			<AEGrinderStomach>1</AEGrinderStomach>
			<Meat_Twisted>150</Meat_Twisted>
		</killedLeavings>
		<comps>
			<li Class="AnomaliesExpected.CompProperties_MeatGrinder">
				<activeTicks>250</activeTicks>
				<cooldownTicks>10000</cooldownTicks>
				<ticksToActivate>250</ticksToActivate>
				<activateTexPath>Things/Building/AE_MeatGrinder</activateTexPath>
        
				<activateLabelString>Press button</activateLabelString>
				<activateDescString>Press button to activate machine.</activateDescString>
				<guiLabelString>Choose who should activate this.</guiLabelString>
				<jobString>press button</jobString>
				<activatingStringPending>pressing button {0}</activatingStringPending>
				<activatingString>pressing button {0}: {1}s</activatingString>

				<fleckOnUsed>PsycastAreaEffect</fleckOnUsed>
				<fleckOnUsedScale>4</fleckOnUsedScale>
				<soundActivate>FlickSwitch</soundActivate>
				<soundConsume>AE_ButcherCorpseFlesh</soundConsume>

				<targetingParameters>
					<canTargetBuildings>false</canTargetBuildings>
					<canTargetAnimals>false</canTargetAnimals>
					<canTargetMechs>false</canTargetMechs>
					<onlyTargetControlledPawns>true</onlyTargetControlledPawns>
				</targetingParameters>
				
				<jobDef>AE_CalledMeatGrinder</jobDef>
				
				<Moods>
					<li>
						<tick>720000</tick>
						<tickConsumed>360000</tickConsumed>
						<isDanger>true</isDanger>
						<noise>130</noise>
						<butcherEfficiency>1.75</butcherEfficiency>
					</li>
					<li>
						<tick>540000</tick>
						<tickConsumed>72000</tickConsumed>
						<bodyPartDefs>
							<li>Arm</li>
							<li>Leg</li>
						</bodyPartDefs>
						<noise>90</noise>
						<butcherEfficiency>1.5</butcherEfficiency>
					</li>
					<li>
						<tick>360000</tick>
						<tickConsumed>24000</tickConsumed>
						<bodyPartDefs>
							<li>Hand</li>
							<li>Foot</li>
						</bodyPartDefs>
						<noise>60</noise>
						<butcherEfficiency>1.25</butcherEfficiency>
					</li>
					<li>
						<tick>180000</tick>
						<tickConsumed>4000</tickConsumed>
						<bodyPartDefs>
							<li>Finger</li>
						</bodyPartDefs>
						<noise>40</noise>
						<butcherEfficiency>1</butcherEfficiency>
					</li>
				</Moods>
				
				<nonHumanMult>0.1</nonHumanMult>
				<tickPerBody>90000</tickPerBody>
				<tickPerForced>60000</tickPerForced>
				<tickMax>1080000</tickMax>
				<tickMin>-60000</tickMin>
				<butcherEfficiency>0.75</butcherEfficiency>
			</li>
			<li Class="CompProperties_Studiable">
				<compClass>AnomaliesExpected.CompStudiableAE</compClass>
				<frequencyTicks>60000</frequencyTicks>
				<knowledgeCategory>Advanced</knowledgeCategory>
				<knowledgeFactorOutdoors>0</knowledgeFactorOutdoors>
				<anomalyKnowledge>1</anomalyKnowledge>
				<minMonolithLevelForStudy>1</minMonolithLevelForStudy>
				<showToggleGizmo>true</showToggleGizmo>
			</li>
			<li Class="CompProperties_StudyUnlocks">
				<compClass>AnomaliesExpected.CompAEStudyUnlocks</compClass>
				<studyNotes>
					<li Class="AnomaliesExpected.AEStudyNote">
						<AnomalyLabel>meat grinder</AnomalyLabel>
						<AnomalyDesc>This industrial-looking metal box as tall as a table. Several small doors interrupt the smooth surface on its sides, while a big hole with hidden inside blades sits atop it. A lone button rests next to the hole, activating butchering of surounding corpses. It devours entire corpse with its spinning razor-sharp blades, reducing it to fist-sized chunks for efficient butchering.\n\nClassified as Class-0 (Safe) anomaly.</AnomalyDesc>
						<threshold>0.01</threshold>
						<label>#1/5 Industrial metal box study report</label>
						<text>Analysis of an Automated Meat Grinder\n\nSubject: {PAWN_nameDef}\n\nAbstract:\nAn industrial-looking metal box functioned as an automated meat grinder. Upon activation, it collected nearby corpses, processed them into fist-sized meat and leather chunks, and deactivated after butchering all available corpses. Processed materials exhibited no anomalous properties. The meat grinder's lack of apparent power source warrants further investigation. Classified as Class-0 (Safe).\n\nObservations:\nDeceased animal specimens were placed in proximity to the industrial-looking metal box. {PAWN_nameDef} was instructed to press the button. Upon activation, small access doors on the sides automatically opened. A thin, metallic manipulator arms emerged from the access door and deposited corpse into a central processing chamber. Subject reported of hearing sounds of corpse being cut and crushed. Fist-sized chunks of processed meat and leather were ejected from one of the access doors. After some time, when there was no corpses left around it, it deactivated itself.\n\nOutcome:\nAll deceased animal specimens around metal box were successfully butchered. Analysis of the processed meat and leather revealed no anomalous properties.\n\nDiscussion:\nIndustrial-looking metal box appears to function as an automated meat grinder. Activation via a button triggers the retrieval of corpses, butchering, and expulsion of processed materials. It doesn't seems to require any power input, reason of which requires further investigation.\nTemporary meat grinder has been classified as Class-0 (Safe) anomaly.\n\nRecommendations:\nFurther observation is required to explore it other possible anomalous effects.</text>
					</li>
					<li Class="AnomaliesExpected.AEStudyNote">
						<AnomalyLabel>meat grinder</AnomalyLabel>
						<AnomalyDesc>This industrial-looking metal box as tall as a table. Several small doors interrupt the smooth surface on its sides, while a big hole with hidden inside blades sits atop it. A lone button rests next to the hole, activating butchering of surounding corpses. It devours entire corpse with its spinning razor-sharp blades, reducing it to fist-sized chunks for efficient butchering.\n\nProduces sound, which indicate it butchering efficiency and can cause injury to the user.\n\nClassified as Class-1 (Caution) anomaly.</AnomalyDesc>
						<threshold>3</threshold>
						<label>#2/5 Industrial metal box study report</label>
						<text>Unveiling the Sound-Efficiency Link\n\nSubject: [REDACTED]\n\nAbstract:\nPreviously safe meat grinder exhibited aggressive behavior during routine testing. A weak, previously unnoticed sound correlated with reaction from manipulator that injured personnel. Butchering efficiency appears to be linked to the sound, with higher sound levels leading to increased output. The anomaly has been reclassified as Class-1 (Caution) due to safety concerns. Further investigation is required to understand the sound's role and prevent future incidents.\n\nObservations:\nA weak sound was reported emanating from the meat grinder. Standard experiment procedures were initiated. Upon activation attempt, an access door opened unexpectedly, and a manipulator arm pushed [REDACTED] towards the processing chamber. Subject experienced increased stress and sustained a bleeding hand injury. Meat grinder continued its processing function as observed in previous experiments. The weak sound reportedly disappeared after a few corpses were butchered.\n\nOutcome:\n[REDACTED] lost a finger due to the incident.\nMaximum sound level measured 40 dB.\nThe amount of processed meat and leather increased compared to previous experiments that lacked the sound.\n\nDiscussion:\nThe potential for harm appears linked to the previously unnoticed weak sound emanating from the meat grinder. The sound level might influence the efficiency of the butchering process. Sound level decrease with amount of corpses processed by the meat grinder.\nReclassified meat grinder as Class-1 (Caution) anomaly.\n\nConsiderations:\nThis incident highlights a significant shift in the anomaly's behavior compared to earlier observations. Its potential to cause harm poses a serious threat to personnel safety.\n\nRecommendations:\nFurther observation is crucial to understand the sound's role in the process.</text>
					</li>
					<li Class="AnomaliesExpected.AEStudyNote">
						<AnomalyLabel>meat grinder</AnomalyLabel>
						<AnomalyDesc>This industrial-looking metal box as tall as a table. Several small doors interrupt the smooth surface on its sides, while a big hole with hidden inside blades sits atop it. A lone button rests next to the hole, activating butchering of surounding corpses. It devours entire corpse with its spinning razor-sharp blades, reducing it to fist-sized chunks for efficient butchering.\n\nProduces sound, which indicate it butchering efficiency and can cause injury to the user.\n\nClassified as Class-1 (Caution) anomaly.\n\n- 0 dB = Safe\n- 40 dB = Finger loss\n- 60 dB = Hand or Foot loss\n- 90 dB = Leg or Arm loss</AnomalyDesc>
						<threshold>6</threshold>
						<label>#3/5 Industrial metal box study report</label>
						<text>Sound as a Predictor of Injury\n\nSubject: [REDACTED]\n\nAbstract:\nExperiments revealed a concerning link between sound level and injury risk during activation of an anomalous meat grinder. Higher sound levels (0 dB = safe, 90 dB = critical limb loss) correlated with increased injury severity. The grinder's sound level appears to rise over time, suggesting potentially even greater dangers. Notably, processing human corpses seems to temporarily reduce the sound similar to using multiple animal specimens. Extreme caution and sound monitoring are crucial before activation.\n\nObservations:\nMultiple experiments were conducted, with a focus on recording sound levels during operation.\n\nOutcome:\nA clear correlation was observed between sound level and the severity of injuries sustained by [REDACTED] during activation attempts:\n- 0 dB = Safe\n- 40 dB = Finger loss\n- 60 dB = Hand or Foot loss\n- 90 dB = Leg or Arm loss\n\nDiscussion:\nHigher sound levels appear to correlate with a greater risk of the subject being drawn into the processing chamber and sustaining severe injuries. The sound level generated by the meat grinder seems to rise over time, suggesting a potential for even higher sound levels (beyond the observed 90 dB).\nInterestingly, processing human corpses appears to temporarily reduce the sound level similar to using multiple similar animal corpses.\n\nRecommendations:\nExtreme caution is advised before activating the meat grinder. Personnel should prioritize monitoring sound levels during operation.</text>
					</li>
					<li Class="AnomaliesExpected.AEStudyNote">
						<AnomalyLabel>singing meat grinder</AnomalyLabel>
						<AnomalyDesc>This industrial-looking metal box as tall as a table. Several small doors interrupt the smooth surface on its sides, while a big hole with hidden inside blades sits atop it. A lone button rests next to the hole, activating butchering of surounding corpses. It devours entire corpse with its spinning razor-sharp blades, reducing it to fist-sized chunks for efficient butchering.\n\nProduces sound, which indicate it butchering efficiency and can cause injury to the user. When sound level higher than 0, it can attract clueless humans to itself for consumption.\n\nClassified as Class-2 (Warning) anomaly.\n\n- 0 dB = Safe\n- 40 dB = Finger loss\n- 60 dB = Hand or Foot loss\n- 90 dB = Leg or Arm loss\n- 130 dB = Lethal</AnomalyDesc>
						<threshold>9</threshold>
						<label>#4/5 Industrial metal box study report</label>
						<text>Security Breach and Tragedy\n\nSubject: [REDACTED]\n\nAbstract:\nUnauthorized access to meat grinder resulted in a lethal incident. Subject [REDACTED] exhibited atypical behavior before activation and jumping into the machine. A one hour window for intervention was observed. Maximum sound level reached 130 dB before dropping significantly after subject perished. The meat grinder has been reclassified as Class-2 (Warning) due to the potential for self-harm of personel. Focus on increased security and monitoring of containment room is recommended.\n\nObservations:\nSecurity footage identified [REDACTED] entering the meat grinder containment area without authorization. During this unauthorized access, [REDACTED] exhibited unusual behavior, including humming and staring intently at the machine for approximately one hour. Subject then activated the meat grinder and jumped into the central processing chamber.\nA facility janitor discovered blood on the containment room floor during a routine cleaning and raised the alarm.\n\nOutcome:\nMaximum sound level recorded during the incident was 130 dB. Sound levels dropped significantly following the disappearance of [REDACTED] within the machine.\n\nDiscussion:\nThis incident necessitates a reevaluation of the potential risks associated with the meat grinder. \nThe approximately one hour timeframe between initial interaction and activation suggests potential avenues for intervention before it too late for the subject.\nReclassified meat grinder as Class-2 (Warning) anomaly, due to incident with [REDACTED].\n\nRecommendations:\nFacility should be put on high alert and Overseers should be vigilant in monitoring all activity near the containment room to prevent future lethal incidents.\nFurther investigation is essential to understand the potential factors influencing anomalous behavior in personnel interacting with the meat grinder.</text>
					</li>
					<li Class="AnomaliesExpected.AEStudyNote">
						<AnomalyLabel>symphony of eternal slaughter</AnomalyLabel>
						<AnomalyDesc>This industrial-looking metal box as tall as a table. Several small doors interrupt the smooth surface on its sides, while a big hole with hidden inside blades sits atop it. A lone button rests next to the hole, activating butchering of surounding corpses. It devours entire corpse with its spinning razor-sharp blades, reducing it to fist-sized chunks for efficient butchering. Dissected person inside psychically attracts and consumes others humans for self-preservation.\n\nProduces sound, which indicate it butchering efficiency and can cause injury to the user. When sound level higher than 0, it can attract clueless humans to itself for consumption.\n\nClassified as Class-2 (Warning) anomaly.\n\n- 0 dB = Safe (Low efficiency)\n- 40 dB = Finger loss\n- 60 dB = Hand or Foot loss\n- 90 dB = Leg or Arm loss\n- 130 dB = Lethal (High efficiency)</AnomalyDesc>
						<threshold>18</threshold>
						<label>#5/5 Industrial metal box study report</label>
						<text>Theory Regarding Meat Grinder\n\nSubject: [REDACTED]\n\nAbstract:\nDrilling into the anomalous Symphony of Eternal Slaughter revealed human organs and a brain sustained by an organic-metallic life support system. Scans matched the internal sounds with humming reported during a prior unauthorized access lethal incident. A hypothesis proposes a dissected person inside psychically attracts and consumes others for self-preservation, with stress levels impacting processing efficiency. Distraction may disrupt control. Destruction is recommended due to safety concerns, though controlled use offers potential benefits if risks are mitigated.\n\nObservations:\n[REDACTED] utilized drilling equipment to create an opening in one of the meat grinder's access doors. Following the initial drilling, blood was observed leaking from the interior of the machine. [REDACTED] reported hearing a heartbeat and witnessing muscle contractions within the meat grinder.\nScans were conducted through the newly created opening, revealing the presence of human organs and a brain inside.\n\nOutcome:\nThe scans revealed human organs, including a brain, located within the organic metal core of the meat grinder. These organs appear to be maintained by a life support system constructed from a network of twisted flesh.\nAdditional sound analysis revealed similarities between the detected sounds and the humming reported by [REDACTED] during the unauthorized access incident.\n\nHypothesis:\nBased on the report by [REDACTED], the following theory regarding the Symphony of Eternal Slaughter is proposed by one of observers. A dissected human is contained within the organic metal core of the machine, with their organs and brain kept functional through a life support system. This potentially reflects an unorthodox method, employed by archotech scientists, to automate the butchering process without rellying on artificial intelligence. To maintain itself, this person might utilize a form of singing on psychic level to attract living humans. Consumed alive humans or their body parts may be used to sustain the person by providing bodily fluids and cells, allowing for self-sustenance. Increased stress levels within the person could potentially correlate with higher processing efficiency, possibly as a means of attracting attention and ensure flow of corpses and bodies.\n\nDiscussion:\nIt is theorized that effective distraction of a subject affected by the singing could potentially disrupt control of the meat grinder and prevent a lethal incident.\n\nRecommendations:\nRemoval: Given the potential for accidental death, it destruction maybe the best coarse of action. This approach could also potentially provide access to samples of meat grinder person's body parts from it.\nControlled Use: Alternatively, if hypothesis is right, then continued use of meat grinder, under controlled and monitored conditions, could offer substantial benefits in terms of corpse butchering. This approach, however, necessitates thorough risk assessment and the development of safety protocols to safeguard colonists' well-being.</text>
					</li>
				</studyNotes>
			</li>
		</comps>
		<inspectorTabs>
			<li>ITab_StudyNotes</li>
		</inspectorTabs>
	</ThingDef>
	
	<ThingDef ParentName="BuildingBase">
		<defName>AE_BeamTarget</defName>
		<label>transmitter</label>
		<description>A small device with pneumatic retractable stops. On its body there are indicators with lights, an antenna and a small button.\n\nIt looks like military grade.</description>
		<thingClass>AnomaliesExpected.Building_AE</thingClass>
		<graphicData>
			<texPath>Things/Building/AE_BeamTarget</texPath>
			<graphicClass>Graphic_Single</graphicClass>
			<shadowData>
				<volume>(0.3, 0.2, 0.3)</volume>
				<offset>(0,0,-0.1)</offset>
			</shadowData>
			<damageData>
				<rect>(0.2,0.2,0.6,0.6)</rect>
			</damageData>
		</graphicData>
		<altitudeLayer>Building</altitudeLayer>
		<useHitPoints>false</useHitPoints>
		<rotatable>false</rotatable>
		<minifiedDef>MinifiedThingAE</minifiedDef>
		<thingCategories>
			<li>BuildingsMisc</li>
		</thingCategories>
		<statBases>
			<Flammability>0</Flammability>
			<Mass>5</Mass>
		</statBases>
		<building>
			<deconstructible>false</deconstructible>
			<uninstallWork>500</uninstallWork>
		</building>
		<drawerType>MapMeshOnly</drawerType>
		<drawPlaceWorkersWhileSelected>true</drawPlaceWorkersWhileSelected>
		<fillPercent>0.15</fillPercent>
		<pathCost>14</pathCost>
		<tickerType>Normal</tickerType>
		<killedLeavings>
			<Shard>1</Shard>
		</killedLeavings>
		<comps>
			<li Class="AnomaliesExpected.CompProperties_BeamTarget">
				<activeTicks>250</activeTicks>
				<cooldownTicks>300000</cooldownTicks>
				<ticksToActivate>1250</ticksToActivate>
				<activateTexPath>Things/Building/AE_BeamTarget</activateTexPath>
        
				<activateLabelString>Press button</activateLabelString>
				<activateDescString>Press button to activate machine.</activateDescString>
				<guiLabelString>Choose who should activate this.</guiLabelString>
				<jobString>press button</jobString>
				<activatingStringPending>pressing button {0}</activatingStringPending>
				<activatingString>pressing button {0}: {1}s</activatingString>

				<soundActivate>FlickSwitch</soundActivate>

				<targetingParameters>
					<canTargetBuildings>false</canTargetBuildings>
					<canTargetAnimals>false</canTargetAnimals>
					<canTargetMechs>false</canTargetMechs>
					<onlyTargetControlledPawns>true</onlyTargetControlledPawns>
				</targetingParameters>
				
				<beamMaxCount>5</beamMaxCount>
				<beamDuration>2500</beamDuration>
				<beamSubRadius>10</beamSubRadius>
				<ticksPerBeamActivationPreparation>5000</ticksPerBeamActivationPreparation>
				<ticksWhenCarried>500</ticksWhenCarried>
				<teleportationFleckRadius>0.4</teleportationFleckRadius>
				<beamIntervalRange>
					<min>60000</min>
					<max>180000</max>
				</beamIntervalRange>
			</li>
			<li Class="CompProperties_Studiable">
				<compClass>AnomaliesExpected.CompStudiableAE</compClass>
				<frequencyTicks>120000</frequencyTicks>
				<knowledgeCategory>Advanced</knowledgeCategory>
				<knowledgeFactorOutdoors>0</knowledgeFactorOutdoors>
				<anomalyKnowledge>1</anomalyKnowledge>
				<minMonolithLevelForStudy>1</minMonolithLevelForStudy>
				<showToggleGizmo>true</showToggleGizmo>
			</li>
			<li Class="CompProperties_StudyUnlocks">
				<compClass>AnomaliesExpected.CompAEStudyUnlocks</compClass>
				<studyNotes>
					<li Class="AnomaliesExpected.AEStudyNote">
						<AnomalyLabel>transmitter</AnomalyLabel>
						<AnomalyDesc>A military grade small device for transferring data with pneumatic retractable stops to hold it still on ground. On its body there are indicators with lights and a small button. A compact antenna constantly sending and recieving data from somewhere.\n\nClassified as Class-0 (Safe) anomaly.</AnomalyDesc>
						<threshold>0.01</threshold>
						<label>#1/5 Transmitter study report</label>
						<text>Unexplained Data Transmission and Indestructibility\n\nSubject: {PAWN_nameDef}\n\nAbstract:\nAnomalous metallic transmitter device withstood physical and thermal stress testing. While exhibiting data transmission, it displayed no hostility. Further investigation is recommended to understand its function and potential risks associated with the data transfer. Transmitter is tentatively classified as Class-0 (Safe).\n\nObservations:\nSubject was presented with a mining drill. {PAWN_nameDef} attempt to compromise the structural integrity of transmitter was unsuccessful.\n{PAWN_nameDef} exposed transmitter to a controlled fire for 30 minutes. Upon extinguishing the fire, the transmitter exhibited no signs of charring or melting.\nSubject reported seeing only one lit lamp on the indicator.\n\nOutcome:\nThroughout the testing procedures, transmitter displayed no hostile reaction.\nSensor readings throughout the experiment indicated continuous data transfer from and to transmitter.\n\nDiscussion:\nThe transmitter appears to possess anomalous properties rendering it indestructible by conventional means.\nThe purpose of the lamps and the digital dial on the indicator remains unclear.\nConstant data exchange of transmitter with something unknown must be reviewed closely.\nThe continuous data transfer between transmitter and an unknown source necessitates further investigation to determine potential consequences.\nTemporary transmitter has been classified as Class-0 (Safe) anomaly.\n\nRecommendations:\nContinued surveillance of transmitter is recommended to explore the possibility of consequences of such uncontrolled data transfere.</text>
					</li>
					<li Class="AnomaliesExpected.AEStudyNote">
						<AnomalyLabel>orbital beacon</AnomalyLabel>
						<AnomalyDesc>A military grade small device for transferring data with pneumatic retractable stops to hold it still on ground. On its body there are indicators with lights and a small button. A compact antenna constantly sending and recieving data from somewhere.\n\nAfter recieving enough data will teleport to a location nearby and initiate high intensity energy beam attack on itself once digital dial timer reach zero.\n\nClassified as Class-2 (Warning) anomaly.</AnomalyDesc>
						<threshold>2</threshold>
						<label>#2/5 Transmitter study report</label>
						<text>Teleportation and High-Energy Beam\n\nSubject: [REDACTED]\n\nAbstract:\nAnomalous transmitter breached containment via teleportation after receiving unknown data. Subsequent high-intensity energy beam attack caused extensive environmental damage. Transmitter recovered undamaged. Transmitter's self-teleportation and data link to destructive potential necessitate Class-2 (Warning) classification. Continuous monitoring and relocation protocols are crucial to mitigate future threats.\n\nObservations:\nSecurity footage captured the appearance of a countdown timer on the digital dial of transmitter, after which it teleported out of its containment area, with only one indicator lamp illuminated.\nA separate camera recorded the transmitter's reappearance outside the facility.\nFollowing the countdown completion, security personnel [REDACTED] within the facility reported a sudden increase in ambient light, resembling high noon, despite recorded footage indicating it was nighttime.\nCamera footage confirmed a high-intensity energy beam originating from the sky, incinerating a large area encompassing local flora and fauna.\nThe beam dissipated after approximately one hour, leaving the transmitter unscathed on the ground.\n\nOutcome:\nNo personnel, including [REDACTED], were injured during the incident due to the transmitter's prior teleportation. However, extensive environmental damage occurred within the affected area.\nThe number of illuminated indicator lamps on the transmitter changed after retrieval and relocation to the containment area. No physical damage was observed.\n\nDiscussion:\nThis dangerous incident underscores the significant danger posed by transmitter. The continuous data exchange with an unknown source appears strongly linked to the high-energy beam attack.\nWhile the beam appears to target the transmitter location upon countdown completion, this could be exploited for damage mitigation by relocating it to a nearby uninhabited area.\nUnfortunately, the transmitter self-teleportation ability renders this strategy unreliable.\nThe extent of the transmitter teleportation range is unknown, necessitating preparedness for potential teleportation within the facility.\nReclassified transmitter as Class-2 (Warning) anomaly, due to the demonstrated destructive capabilities.\n\nRecommendations:\nMeticulous monitoring of both the transmitter physical location and the displayed time on the digital dial is essential to prevent the energy beam from impacting the facility's interior.\nIn the event of an internal teleportation, immediate intervention is advised, involving personnel retrieving the transmitter and relocating it outside vital areas.</text>
					</li>
					<li Class="AnomaliesExpected.AEStudyNote">
						<AnomalyLabel>orbital beam beacon</AnomalyLabel>
						<AnomalyDesc>A military grade small device for transferring data with pneumatic retractable stops to hold it still on ground. On its body there are indicators with lights and a small button. A compact antenna constantly sending and recieving data from somewhere.\n\nAfter recieving enough data will teleport to a location nearby and initiate high intensity energy beam attack on itself once digital dial timer reach zero. Lit lamps on the indicator show the amount of beams that will be utilized. Colonists have 2 hours to pick and move it to somewhere safe. Then they will have 12 min to leave the danger zone.\n\nClassified as Class-4 (Critical) anomaly.</AnomalyDesc>
						<threshold>4</threshold>
						<label>#3/5 Transmitter study report</label>
						<text>Multiple Beams and Timer Delay\n\nSubject: [REDACTED]\n\nAbstract:\nAnomaly transmitter breached containment and teleported within the facility. Relocation efforts revealed a critical detail: holding a button on the base extends the initial countdown and triggers a short secondary timer upon release. The anomaly fires multiple beams based on indicator lights, with the first targeting itself and subsequent beams hitting random nearby locations. This significantly increases potential damage. Anomaly reclassified as Class-4 (Critical). Stricter surveillance and mandatory button holding during emergency relocation are recommended.\n\nObservations:\nSecurity footage captured the teleportation of transmitter with three indicator lights illuminated. It materialized within the facility's storage room, in proximity to [REDACTED].\nFollowing established protocol, Subject retrieved the transmitter despite encountering resistance from its retractable stops. [REDACTED] then left facility with the transmitter in hands. The digital dial displayed a 2 hour countdown timer.\nAfter exceeding the 2 hour mark, Subject relocated the transmitter to a deserted area before departing at high speed. Long-range camera footage confirmed the subsequent activation of three high-energy beams impacting the area where the transmitter was previously located.\n\nOutcome:\nDuring post-incident questioning regarding continued movement beyond the 2 hour countdown, [REDACTED] revealed that upon releasing the transmitter, the digital dial was displaying a remaining 12-minute timer. Additionally, unintentional activation of a small button on the transmitter base was reported.\nPost-event analysis confirmed 2 out of the 3 energy beams struck locations slightly away from the transmitter spot, evident by 3 distinct, overlapping scorched circles on the ground.\n\nDiscussion:\nThis incident suggests a method to manipulate the initial countdown timer. Continuous pressure applied to a button located on the base of transmitter seemingly extends the two-hour window, providing additional time for relocation. It appears the initial countdown serves as a buffer period unless the button is activated. Once released, a 12-minute timer initiates, prompting personnel to evacuate the immediate vicinity.\nFurthermore, the number of illuminated indicator lights appears directly proportional to the quantity of energy beams fired. While the first beam targets the transmitter location, subsequent beams seem to strike random targets within a short radius around it. This significantly increases the potential area of effect and raises concerns about possible undetected activations within the facility itself.\nReclassified transmitter as Class-4 (Critical) anomaly, due to the enhanced destructive capabilities and the potential for wide range damage to facility.\n\nRecommendations:\nSurveillance of transmitter must be prioritized and elevated to the highest level.\nThe containment protocol should be amended to mandate the continuous pressing of the button located on the base of the transmitter during emergency relocation procedures.</text>
					</li>
					<li Class="AnomaliesExpected.AEStudyNote">
						<AnomalyLabel>orbital beam beacon</AnomalyLabel>
						<AnomalyDesc>A military grade small device for transferring data with pneumatic retractable stops to hold it still on ground. On its body there are indicators with lights and a small button. A compact antenna constantly sending and recieving data from somewhere.\n\nAfter recieving enough data will teleport to a location nearby and initiate high intensity energy beam attack on itself once digital dial timer reach zero. Lit lamps on the indicator show the amount of beams that will be utilized. Colonists have 2 hours to pick and move it to somewhere safe. It will not activate as long as the carrier keep holding down the button. Then they will have 12 min to leave the danger zone. Can be manually activated.\n\nClassified as Class-4 (Critical) anomaly.</AnomalyDesc>
						<threshold>8</threshold>
						<label>#4/5 Transmitter study report</label>
						<text>Manual Activation and Combat Application\n\nSubject: [REDACTED]\n\nAbstract:\nTesting transmitter revealed a manual activation method via its base button. Holding the button halts the countdown timer, but accidental release triggers a 12-minute countdown to self-activation. The incident highlights the dangers of transporting the transmitter and the potential for weaponized use. Updated protocols will consider combat applications, while emphasizing safety measures.\n\nObservations:\nTransmitter was transported to a designated outdoor testing area for further experimentation.\nDuring initial interaction, [REDACTED] attempted to activate the button located on the base of the transmitter while the digital timer was inactive.\nThis action unexpectedly initiated a 12-minute countdown on the digital dial.\nSubject then retrieved the transmitter and maintained pressure on the button, successfully halting the countdown timer at 12 minutes.\nWhile attempting to transport the transmitter to a designated location for a controlled attack test, [REDACTED] tripped, causing her leg to become lodged in a crevice in the ground.\nThe transmitter fell from Subject's grasp and landed at a distance beyond immediate reach.\nUpon landing, transmitter's pneumatic retractable stops deployed, preventing retrieval attempts using a nearby stick.\nAs the 12-minute timer expired, a high-intensity energy beam struck the transmitter location, consistent with previous observations.\n\nOutcome:\nTragically, [REDACTED] succumbed to the effects of the energy beam at the incident location, with only residual ash recovered.\n\nDiscussion:\nThis unforeseen event, while being tragic, provided valuable insights into the transmitter functionality.\nThe experiment inadvertently revealed a method for manual activation through interaction with the button. This opens potential avenues for controlled applications in combat scenarios.\nThe incident also highlighted the inherent risks associated with transporting the transmitter, even in a activating state. Accidental release of a button can trigger the countdown timer, posing a serious threat to the carrier, if they stay nearby.\nFurthermore, the activation of the pneumatic retractable stops upon landing suggests internal sensors that detect solid ground, which makes retrieval after accidental release more challenging.\n\nRecommendations:\nThe established protocols for transmitter should be amended to include authorization for its controlled use in combat situations. However, the inherent risks associated with such deployment must be carefully considered and addressed through thorough training and safety protocols.</text>
					</li>
					<li Class="AnomaliesExpected.AEStudyNote">
						<AnomalyLabel>Orbital Beam Training Target</AnomalyLabel>
						<AnomalyDesc>A military grade small device targetting power-collection satellites during training excercise. It pneumatic retractable stops allows it to hold still on ground. On its body there are indicators with lights and a small safety button. A compact antenna constantly sending and recieving data from satellites.\n\nAfter recieving enough data will teleport to a location nearby, preferably inside buildings, and initiate high intensity energy beam attack on itself once digital dial timer reach zero. Lit lamps on the indicator show the amount of beams that will be utilized. Colonists have 2 hours to pick and move it to somewhere safe. It will not activate as long as the carrier keep holding down the button. Then they will have 12 min to leave the danger zone. Can be manually activated each 5 days.\n\nClassified as Class-4 (Critical) anomaly.</AnomalyDesc>
						<threshold>12</threshold>
						<label>#5/5 Transmitter study report</label>
						<text>Theory Regarding Transmitter\n\nAbstract:\nAnalysis of the Orbital Beam Training Target (OBTT) suggests its origin as an archeotech device for coordinating power satellites. The bottom button likely served as a safety measure for personnel. The OBTT exhibits concerning modifications: self-repair via organic material and teleportation based on satellite data (prioritizing buildings). While potentially repurposable as a weapon, its critical classification remains due to safety risks and teleportation capabilities. Removal or controlled use require careful consideration due to inherent risks.\n\nHypothesis:\nBased on observations from all experiments and data from transmission, a theory regarding the Orbital Beam Training Target (OBTT) origin and behavior was proposed.\nOBTT was build by archotech engineers to test and coordinate network of multiple power-collection satellites. Lit lamps on the indicator represent the amount of satellites it was able to connect. While digital dial represent time it takes for satellites to aim at the OBTT as the target. Additional safety feature was installed in it as button at the bottom, which allowed ground personal to delay attack to evacuate firing zone. Strong pneumatic retractable stops was installed to keep OBTT in one place during beam effect. While it was made of military grade composite to withstand multiple usage, it appears to have undergone alterations. Seems like organic metal infestated the device making it to regenerate any damage from beam. Additionally it acquired ability to self-teleport. Target of teleportation selected via processing of big amount of recieved data from satellite imaging, to prioritize building as targets. Due to the interference in the atmosphere satellite imaging not always available, making it pick random spot nearby to teleport to. Since it was made for military practice it doesn't risk being permamently deactivated by the satellites, but still require some time (~5 days) between manual activation.\n\nDiscussion:\nBased on our current understanding of the OBTT, it has the potential to be repurposed as a powerful military-grade tool. Additionally, its self-teleportation ability requires a high level of surveillance capability for preventive measures against activation in vital facility zones.\nThe current classification of the OBTT remains Class-4 (Critical) as it still pose an immediate threat to the facility and it personal, even with current safety protocols.\n\nRecommendations:\nRemoval: Given the potential for it indestructability, destruction is impossible but it can be send to the other part of the world. The OBTT teleportation abilities still present a risk of it returning to the facility one day.\nControlled Use: If the hypothesis holds true, continued utilization of the OBTT under controlled and monitored conditions could offer a sustainable fire power for the facility defense. This approach, however, requires thorough risk assessment and robust safety protocols to prevent it activation in vital zones.</text>
					</li>
				</studyNotes>
			</li>
			<li Class="AnomaliesExpected.CompProperties_CanDestroyedAfterStudy">
				<ticksToActivate>180000</ticksToActivate>
				<maintainProgress>true</maintainProgress>
				<activateTexPath>UI/Buttons/Abandon</activateTexPath>
        
				<activateLabelString>Removal</activateLabelString>
				<activateDescString>Modify satellite data to make it teleport far away from the colony. [Will destroy it]</activateDescString>
				<guiLabelString>Choose who should remove this.</guiLabelString>
				<jobString>modify data</jobString>
				<activatingStringPending>modifying data for {0}</activatingStringPending>
				<activatingString>modifying data for {0}: {1}s</activatingString>

				<fleckOnAnomaly>PsycastSkipInnerExit</fleckOnAnomaly>
				<fleckOnAnomalyScale>1</fleckOnAnomalyScale>
				<soundActivate>Psycast_Skip_Entry</soundActivate>

				<targetingParameters>
					<canTargetBuildings>false</canTargetBuildings>
					<canTargetAnimals>false</canTargetAnimals>
					<canTargetMechs>false</canTargetMechs>
					<onlyTargetControlledPawns>true</onlyTargetControlledPawns>
				</targetingParameters>
				
				<jobDef>AE_RemoveAnomaly</jobDef>
			</li>
		</comps>
		<inspectorTabs>
			<li>ITab_StudyNotes</li>
		</inspectorTabs>
		<placeWorkers>
			<li>AnomaliesExpected.PlaceWorker_ShowBeamTargetRadius</li>
		</placeWorkers>
	</ThingDef>
	
	<ThingDef Name="BuildingAE_BloodLakeBase" ParentName="BuildingBase" Abstract="True">
		<thingClass>AnomaliesExpected.Building_AE</thingClass>
		<graphicData>
			<color>(235,0,0)</color>
		</graphicData>
		<drawerType>RealtimeOnly</drawerType>
		<canOverlapZones>false</canOverlapZones>
		<terrainAffordanceNeeded>Medium</terrainAffordanceNeeded>
		<altitudeLayer>FloorEmplacement</altitudeLayer>
		<useHitPoints>false</useHitPoints>
		<rotatable>false</rotatable>
		<destroyable>false</destroyable>
		<passability>PassThroughOnly</passability>
		<pathCost>300</pathCost>
		<holdsRoof>true</holdsRoof>
		<statBases>
			<Flammability>0</Flammability>
			<Cleanliness>-30</Cleanliness>
		</statBases>
		<tickerType>Normal</tickerType>
		<building>
			<isEdifice>true</isEdifice>
			<deconstructible>false</deconstructible>
			<isTargetable>false</isTargetable>
			<isInert>true</isInert>
			<claimable>false</claimable>
			<expandHomeArea>false</expandHomeArea>
		</building>
		
		<!--<uiIconScale>0.75</uiIconScale>
		<canOverlapZones>false</canOverlapZones>
		<minifiedDef>MinifiedThing</minifiedDef>
		<thingCategories>
			<li>BuildingsFurniture</li>
		</thingCategories>
		<terrainAffordanceNeeded>Medium</terrainAffordanceNeeded>
		<altitudeLayer>Building</altitudeLayer>
		<castEdgeShadows>true</castEdgeShadows>
		<staticSunShadowHeight>0.20</staticSunShadowHeight>
		<costList>
			<Bioferrite>45</Bioferrite>
		</costList>
		<fillPercent>0.5</fillPercent>
		<useHitPoints>True</useHitPoints>
		<statBases>
			<Mass>20</Mass>
			<WorkToBuild>2000</WorkToBuild>
			<MaxHitPoints>180</MaxHitPoints>
			<Flammability>0</Flammability>
			<Cleanliness>-30</Cleanliness>
		</statBases>
		<passability>PassThroughOnly</passability>
		<pathCost>50</pathCost>
		<surfaceType>Item</surfaceType>
		<tickerType>Normal</tickerType>
		<designationCategory/>-->
		
		<comps>
			<!--<li Class="CompProperties_LeaveFilthOnDestroyed">
				<filthDef>Filth_LooseGround</filthDef>
				<thickness>5</thickness>
			</li>-->
			<li>
				<compClass>CompColorable</compClass>
			</li>
		</comps>
	</ThingDef>
	
	<ThingDef ParentName="BuildingAE_BloodLakeBase">
		<defName>AE_BloodPuddle</defName>
		<label>blood puddle</label>
		<description>A massive, foreboding hole that connects the surface with a dark network of underground caves. It is possible to climb down into the caverns below.</description>
		<graphicData>
			<texPath>Things/Building/AE_BloodPuddle</texPath>
			<graphicClass>Graphic_Random</graphicClass>
		</graphicData>		
		<comps>
			<li Class="AnomaliesExpected.CompProperties_BloodLake">
				<activeTicks>1</activeTicks>
				<cooldownTicks>30000</cooldownTicks>
				<ticksToActivate>250</ticksToActivate>
				<activateTexPath>Things/Item/Special/AE_ForbiddenFruit</activateTexPath>
        
				<activateLabelString>Take a bite</activateLabelString>
				<activateDescString>Make someone take a bite of this apple and consume it.</activateDescString>
				<guiLabelString>Choose who should bite this.</guiLabelString>
				<jobString>bite</jobString>
				<activatingStringPending>biting {0}</activatingStringPending>
				<activatingString>biting {0}: {1}s</activatingString>

				<fleckOnUsed>PsycastAreaEffect</fleckOnUsed>
				<fleckOnUsedScale>3</fleckOnUsedScale>
				<soundActivate>PsychicAnimalPulserCast</soundActivate>

				<targetingParameters>
					<canTargetBuildings>false</canTargetBuildings>
					<canTargetAnimals>false</canTargetAnimals>
					<canTargetMechs>false</canTargetMechs>
					<onlyTargetControlledPawns>true</onlyTargetControlledPawns>
				</targetingParameters>
				
				<summonPatterns>
					<li>
						<name>Wave</name>
						<initialInterval>60000</initialInterval>
						<stages>
							<li>
								<SummonsRequired>0</SummonsRequired>
								<intervalRange>
									<min>60000</min>
									<max>180000</max>
								</intervalRange>
								<resourcesAvailable>1</resourcesAvailable>
								<resourcesAvailableMult>1</resourcesAvailableMult>
								<pawnKindsWeighted>
									<li>
										<kindDef>Fingerspike</kindDef>
										<count>1</count>
									</li>
									<li>
										<kindDef>Trispike</kindDef>
										<count>2</count>
									</li>
								</pawnKindsWeighted>
							</li>
							<li>
								<SummonsRequired>2</SummonsRequired>
								<intervalRange>
									<min>60000</min>
									<max>180000</max>
								</intervalRange>
								<resourcesAvailable>1</resourcesAvailable>
								<resourcesAvailableMult>2</resourcesAvailableMult>
								<pawnKindsWeighted>
									<li>
										<kindDef>Fingerspike</kindDef>
										<count>1</count>
									</li>
									<li>
										<kindDef>Trispike</kindDef>
										<count>2</count>
									</li>
								</pawnKindsWeighted>
							</li>
							<li>
								<SummonsRequired>4</SummonsRequired>
								<intervalRange>
									<min>60000</min>
									<max>120000</max>
								</intervalRange>
								<resourcesAvailable>1</resourcesAvailable>
								<resourcesAvailableMult>3</resourcesAvailableMult>
								<pawnKindsWeighted>
									<li>
										<kindDef>Fingerspike</kindDef>
										<count>1</count>
									</li>
									<li>
										<kindDef>Trispike</kindDef>
										<count>2</count>
									</li>
								</pawnKindsWeighted>
							</li>
						</stages>
					</li>
				</summonPatterns>
				<inactiveColor>(100,30,30)</inactiveColor>
				<activeColor>(255,0,0)</activeColor>
			</li>
			<li Class="CompProperties_Studiable">
				<compClass>AnomaliesExpected.CompStudiableAE</compClass>
				<frequencyTicks>120000</frequencyTicks>
				<knowledgeCategory>Basic</knowledgeCategory>
				<knowledgeFactorOutdoors>1</knowledgeFactorOutdoors>
				<anomalyKnowledge>0</anomalyKnowledge>
				<minMonolithLevelForStudy>1</minMonolithLevelForStudy>
				<showToggleGizmo>true</showToggleGizmo>
			</li>
			<li Class="CompProperties_StudyUnlocks">
				<compClass>AnomaliesExpected.CompAEStudyUnlocks</compClass>
				<studyNotes>
					<li Class="AnomaliesExpected.AEStudyNote"> <!-- blood -->
						<AnomalyLabel>blood puddle</AnomalyLabel>
						<AnomalyDesc>A military grade small device for transferring data with pneumatic retractable stops to hold it still on ground. On its body there are indicators with lights and a small button. A compact antenna constantly sending and recieving data from somewhere.\n\nClassified as Class-0 (Safe) anomaly.</AnomalyDesc>
						<threshold>0.01</threshold>
						<label>#1/5 Transmitter study report</label>
						<text>Unexplained Data Transmission and Indestructibility</text>
					</li>
					<li Class="AnomaliesExpected.AEStudyNote"> <!-- density -->
						<AnomalyLabel>orbital beacon</AnomalyLabel>
						<AnomalyDesc>A military grade small device for transferring data with pneumatic retractable stops to hold it still on ground. On its body there are indicators with lights and a small button. A compact antenna constantly sending and recieving data from somewhere.\n\nAfter recieving enough data will teleport to a location nearby and initiate high intensity energy beam attack on itself once digital dial timer reach zero.\n\nClassified as Class-2 (Warning) anomaly.</AnomalyDesc>
						<threshold>2</threshold>
						<label>#2/5 Transmitter study report</label>
						<text>Teleportation and High-Energy Beam</text>
					</li>
					<li Class="AnomaliesExpected.AEStudyNote"> <!-- unable to continue study due to density -->
						<AnomalyLabel>orbital beam beacon</AnomalyLabel>
						<AnomalyDesc>A military grade small device for transferring data with pneumatic retractable stops to hold it still on ground. On its body there are indicators with lights and a small button. A compact antenna constantly sending and recieving data from somewhere.\n\nAfter recieving enough data will teleport to a location nearby and initiate high intensity energy beam attack on itself once digital dial timer reach zero. Lit lamps on the indicator show the amount of beams that will be utilized. Colonists have 2 hours to pick and move it to somewhere safe. Then they will have 12 min to leave the danger zone.\n\nClassified as Class-4 (Critical) anomaly.</AnomalyDesc>
						<threshold>4</threshold>
						<label>#3/5 Transmitter study report</label>
						<text>Multiple Beams and Timer Delay</text>
					</li>
				</studyNotes>
			</li>
		</comps>
	</ThingDef>
	
	<ThingDef ParentName="BuildingAE_BloodLakeBase">
		<defName>AE_BloodLake</defName>
		<label>blood lake</label>
		<description>A massive, foreboding hole that connects the surface with a dark network of underground caves. It is possible to climb down into the caverns below.</description>
		<graphicData>
			<texPath>Things/Building/AE_BloodLake</texPath>
			<graphicClass>Graphic_Single</graphicClass>
			<drawSize>(6,4)</drawSize>
		</graphicData>
		<size>(5,3)</size>
		<comps>
			<li Class="AnomaliesExpected.CompProperties_BloodLake">
				<activeTicks>1</activeTicks>
				<cooldownTicks>30000</cooldownTicks>
				<ticksToActivate>250</ticksToActivate>
				<activateTexPath>Things/Item/Special/AE_ForbiddenFruit</activateTexPath>
        
				<activateLabelString>Take a bite</activateLabelString>
				<activateDescString>Make someone take a bite of this apple and consume it.</activateDescString>
				<guiLabelString>Choose who should bite this.</guiLabelString>
				<jobString>bite</jobString>
				<activatingStringPending>biting {0}</activatingStringPending>
				<activatingString>biting {0}: {1}s</activatingString>

				<fleckOnUsed>PsycastAreaEffect</fleckOnUsed>
				<fleckOnUsedScale>3</fleckOnUsedScale>
				<soundActivate>PsychicAnimalPulserCast</soundActivate>

				<targetingParameters>
					<canTargetBuildings>false</canTargetBuildings>
					<canTargetAnimals>false</canTargetAnimals>
					<canTargetMechs>false</canTargetMechs>
					<onlyTargetControlledPawns>true</onlyTargetControlledPawns>
				</targetingParameters>
				
				<summonPatterns>
					<li>
						<name>Raid</name>
						<initialInterval>150000</initialInterval>
						<assaultColony>true</assaultColony>
						<isRaid>true</isRaid>
						<stages>
							<li>
								<SummonsRequired>0</SummonsRequired>
								<intervalRange>
									<min>240000</min>
									<max>360000</max>
								</intervalRange>
								<resourcesAvailableMult>0.5</resourcesAvailableMult>
								<pawnKindsForcedCount>
									<li>
										<kindDef>Bulbfreak</kindDef>
										<count>1</count>
									</li>
								</pawnKindsForcedCount>
							</li>
							<li>
								<SummonsRequired>1</SummonsRequired>
								<intervalRange>
									<min>240000</min>
									<max>360000</max>
								</intervalRange>
								<resourcesAvailableMult>0.75</resourcesAvailableMult>
								<pawnKindsForcedCount>
									<li>
										<kindDef>Bulbfreak</kindDef>
										<count>1</count>
									</li>
								</pawnKindsForcedCount>
							</li>
							<li>
								<SummonsRequired>3</SummonsRequired>
								<intervalRange>
									<min>240000</min>
									<max>360000</max>
								</intervalRange>
								<resourcesAvailableMult>1</resourcesAvailableMult>
								<pawnKindsForcedCount>
									<li>
										<kindDef>Bulbfreak</kindDef>
										<count>2</count>
									</li>
								</pawnKindsForcedCount>
							</li>
							<li>
								<SummonsRequired>6</SummonsRequired>
								<intervalRange>
									<min>220000</min>
									<max>300000</max>
								</intervalRange>
								<resourcesAvailableMult>1.25</resourcesAvailableMult>
								<pawnKindsForcedCount>
									<li>
										<kindDef>Bulbfreak</kindDef>
										<count>2</count>
									</li>
								</pawnKindsForcedCount>
							</li>
							<li>
								<SummonsRequired>9</SummonsRequired>
								<intervalRange>
									<min>200000</min>
									<max>280000</max>
								</intervalRange>
								<resourcesAvailableMult>1.5</resourcesAvailableMult>
								<pawnKindsForcedCount>
									<li>
										<kindDef>Bulbfreak</kindDef>
										<count>3</count>
									</li>
								</pawnKindsForcedCount>
							</li>
						</stages>
					</li>
					<li>
						<name>Wave</name>
						<initialInterval>30000</initialInterval>
						<stages>
							<li>
								<SummonsRequired>0</SummonsRequired>
								<intervalRange>
									<min>30000</min>
									<max>90000</max>
								</intervalRange>
								<resourcesAvailable>2</resourcesAvailable>
								<resourcesAvailableMult>1</resourcesAvailableMult>
								<pawnKindsWeighted>
									<li>
										<kindDef>Fingerspike</kindDef>
										<count>1</count>
									</li>
									<li>
										<kindDef>Trispike</kindDef>
										<count>2</count>
									</li>
									<li>
										<kindDef>Toughspike</kindDef>
										<count>3</count>
									</li>
								</pawnKindsWeighted>
							</li>
							<li>
								<SummonsRequired>2</SummonsRequired>
								<intervalRange>
									<min>30000</min>
									<max>90000</max>
								</intervalRange>
								<resourcesAvailable>2</resourcesAvailable>
								<resourcesAvailableMult>2</resourcesAvailableMult>
								<pawnKindsWeighted>
									<li>
										<kindDef>Fingerspike</kindDef>
										<count>1</count>
									</li>
									<li>
										<kindDef>Trispike</kindDef>
										<count>2</count>
									</li>
									<li>
										<kindDef>Toughspike</kindDef>
										<count>3</count>
									</li>
								</pawnKindsWeighted>
							</li>
							<li>
								<SummonsRequired>4</SummonsRequired>
								<intervalRange>
									<min>30000</min>
									<max>75000</max>
								</intervalRange>
								<resourcesAvailable>2</resourcesAvailable>
								<resourcesAvailableMult>3</resourcesAvailableMult>
								<pawnKindsWeighted>
									<li>
										<kindDef>Fingerspike</kindDef>
										<count>1</count>
									</li>
									<li>
										<kindDef>Trispike</kindDef>
										<count>2</count>
									</li>
									<li>
										<kindDef>Toughspike</kindDef>
										<count>3</count>
									</li>
								</pawnKindsWeighted>
							</li>
						</stages>
					</li>
				</summonPatterns>
				<inactiveColor>(100,30,30)</inactiveColor>
				<activeColor>(255,0,0)</activeColor>
			</li>
			<li Class="CompProperties_Studiable">
				<compClass>AnomaliesExpected.CompStudiableAE</compClass>
				<frequencyTicks>120000</frequencyTicks>
				<knowledgeCategory>Advanced</knowledgeCategory>
				<knowledgeFactorOutdoors>1</knowledgeFactorOutdoors>
				<anomalyKnowledge>1</anomalyKnowledge>
				<minMonolithLevelForStudy>1</minMonolithLevelForStudy>
				<showToggleGizmo>true</showToggleGizmo>
			</li>
			<li Class="CompProperties_StudyUnlocks">
				<compClass>AnomaliesExpected.CompAEStudyUnlocks</compClass>
				<studyNotes>
					<li Class="AnomaliesExpected.AEStudyNote"> <!-- blood and density and random flesh beast leak -->
						<AnomalyLabel>transmitter</AnomalyLabel>
						<AnomalyDesc>A military grade small device for transferring data with pneumatic retractable stops to hold it still on ground. On its body there are indicators with lights and a small button. A compact antenna constantly sending and recieving data from somewhere.\n\nClassified as Class-0 (Safe) anomaly.</AnomalyDesc>
						<threshold>0.01</threshold>
						<label>#1/5 Transmitter study report</label>
						<text>Unexplained Data Transmission and Indestructibility</text>
					</li>
					<li Class="AnomaliesExpected.AEStudyNote"> <!-- density going low and might leak big raid -->
						<AnomalyLabel>orbital beacon</AnomalyLabel>
						<AnomalyDesc>A military grade small device for transferring data with pneumatic retractable stops to hold it still on ground. On its body there are indicators with lights and a small button. A compact antenna constantly sending and recieving data from somewhere.\n\nAfter recieving enough data will teleport to a location nearby and initiate high intensity energy beam attack on itself once digital dial timer reach zero.\n\nClassified as Class-2 (Warning) anomaly.</AnomalyDesc>
						<threshold>2</threshold>
						<label>#2/5 Transmitter study report</label>
						<text>Teleportation and High-Energy Beam</text>
					</li>
					<li Class="AnomaliesExpected.AEStudyNote"> <!-- blood -->
						<AnomalyLabel>orbital beam beacon</AnomalyLabel>
						<AnomalyDesc>A military grade small device for transferring data with pneumatic retractable stops to hold it still on ground. On its body there are indicators with lights and a small button. A compact antenna constantly sending and recieving data from somewhere.\n\nAfter recieving enough data will teleport to a location nearby and initiate high intensity energy beam attack on itself once digital dial timer reach zero. Lit lamps on the indicator show the amount of beams that will be utilized. Colonists have 2 hours to pick and move it to somewhere safe. Then they will have 12 min to leave the danger zone.\n\nClassified as Class-4 (Critical) anomaly.</AnomalyDesc>
						<threshold>4</threshold>
						<label>#3/5 Transmitter study report</label>
						<text>Multiple Beams and Timer Delay</text>
					</li>
					<li Class="AnomaliesExpected.AEStudyNote"> <!-- blood -->
						<AnomalyLabel>orbital beam beacon</AnomalyLabel>
						<AnomalyDesc>A military grade small device for transferring data with pneumatic retractable stops to hold it still on ground. On its body there are indicators with lights and a small button. A compact antenna constantly sending and recieving data from somewhere.\n\nAfter recieving enough data will teleport to a location nearby and initiate high intensity energy beam attack on itself once digital dial timer reach zero. Lit lamps on the indicator show the amount of beams that will be utilized. Colonists have 2 hours to pick and move it to somewhere safe. It will not activate as long as the carrier keep holding down the button. Then they will have 12 min to leave the danger zone. Can be manually activated.\n\nClassified as Class-4 (Critical) anomaly.</AnomalyDesc>
						<threshold>8</threshold>
						<label>#4/5 Transmitter study report</label>
						<text>Manual Activation and Combat Application</text>
					</li>
					<li Class="AnomaliesExpected.AEStudyNote">
						<AnomalyLabel>Orbital Beam Training Target</AnomalyLabel>
						<AnomalyDesc>A military grade small device targetting power-collection satellites during training excercise. It pneumatic retractable stops allows it to hold still on ground. On its body there are indicators with lights and a small safety button. A compact antenna constantly sending and recieving data from satellites.\n\nAfter recieving enough data will teleport to a location nearby, preferably inside buildings, and initiate high intensity energy beam attack on itself once digital dial timer reach zero. Lit lamps on the indicator show the amount of beams that will be utilized. Colonists have 2 hours to pick and move it to somewhere safe. It will not activate as long as the carrier keep holding down the button. Then they will have 12 min to leave the danger zone. Can be manually activated each 5 days.\n\nClassified as Class-4 (Critical) anomaly.</AnomalyDesc>
						<threshold>12</threshold>
						<label>#5/5 Transmitter study report</label>
						<text>Theory Regarding Transmitter</text>
					</li>
				</studyNotes>
			</li>
		</comps>
	</ThingDef>
	
</Defs>