<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Defs>

	<ThingDef ParentName="Bed">
		<defName>AE_AnomalyBed</defName>
		<label>ordinary bed</label>
		<description>A cozy mattress and sheets on a frame made of organic metal for resting.\n\nSeems like the only way to understand it more is for someone to sleep on it.</description>
		<graphicData>
			<texPath>Things/Building/AE_AnomalyBed</texPath>
			<graphicClass>Graphic_Multi</graphicClass>
			<shaderType>CutoutComplex</shaderType>
			<drawSize>(2,2)</drawSize>
			<damageData>
				<rect>(0,0.05,1,1.95)</rect>
			</damageData>
		</graphicData>
		<statBases>
			<Beauty>1</Beauty>
			<BedRestEffectiveness>0.25</BedRestEffectiveness>
			<Comfort>0.25</Comfort>
		</statBases>    
		<stuffCategories Inherit="False"/>
		<costStuffCount/>
		<costList>
			<Bioferrite>45</Bioferrite>
		</costList>
		<tickerType>Rare</tickerType>
		<designationCategory/>
		<comps>
			<li Class="AnomaliesExpected.CompProperties_AnomalyBed"/>
			<li Class="CompProperties_Studiable">
				<compClass>AnomaliesExpected.CompStudiableAE</compClass>
				<frequencyTicks>120000</frequencyTicks>
				<knowledgeCategory>Basic</knowledgeCategory>
				<knowledgeFactorOutdoors>0</knowledgeFactorOutdoors>
				<anomalyKnowledge>0</anomalyKnowledge>
				<minMonolithLevelForStudy>1</minMonolithLevelForStudy>
				<studyEnabledByDefault>false</studyEnabledByDefault>
			</li>
			<li Class="CompProperties_StudyUnlocks">
				<studyNotes>
					<li>
						<threshold>1</threshold>
						<label>#1/3 Ordinary bed study report</label>
						<text>Enhanced Cognitive Function Following Non-Standard Sleep\n\nSubject: {PAWN_nameDef}\n\nAbstract:\nThis report details observations of Subject {PAWN_nameDef} following a period of sleep on ordinary bed. This deviated from the typical sleep protocol within the facility. While Subject exhibited abnormally rapid sleep and atypical brain activity, no adverse effects were noted. Interestingly, upon awakening, {PAWN_nameDef} reported newfound knowledge directly related to ongoing anomalies research in the facility. This information appears unrelated to prior exposure within the facility, suggesting unconventional pathways to data acquisition. Current research protocols may not be optimally suited to study this phenomenon. Further investigation is warranted.\n\nObservations:\n{PAWN_nameDef} was permitted to utilize ordinary bed for sleep, deviating from the standard protocol.\nSleep duration was significantly shorter than the norm for Subject.\nBrainwave patterns deviated from baseline readings during sleep.\nNo negative physical or behavioral changes were observed post-sleep.\n\nFindings:\nUpon awakening, {PAWN_nameDef} reported novel information relevant to ongoing research on anomalies in the facility.\nThe reported information was not previously known to Subject and could not be attributed to standard briefings or exposure within the facility.\n\nDiscussion:\nThese findings suggest a potential correlation between non-standard sleep and enhanced cognitive function, specifically related to anomaly research. Conventional research methods may not be sufficient to explore this phenomenon.\n\nRecommendations:\nFurther experimentation is required to substantiate these observations.  Additional tests with {PAWN_nameDef} and potentially other subjects are recommended to explore the potential of non-standard sleep and acquisition of research-relevant data.</text>
					</li>
					<li>
						<threshold>7</threshold>
						<label>#2/3 Ordinary bed study report</label>
						<text>Potential Correlation with Fatigue of Colonists\n\nAbstract:\nThis report details observations concerning the effects of ordinary bed introduced into a research facility housing colonists. Following its arrival, a significant portion of the colonists exhibited increased fatigue. Notably, the severity of fatigue appeared to correlate directly with the frequency of experiments conducted utilizing the ordinary bed. These findings suggest a potential link between the ordinary bed and colonists well-being. Given this observation, continued experimentation with the ordinary bed is recommended with caution. Further investigation into the bed's properties and its impact on colonists' physiology is warranted.\n\nObservations:\nFollowing the introduction of ordinary bed into the facility, a notable increase in fatigue was observed amongst several colonists.\nThe severity of fatigue appears to be directly proportional to the number of experiments conducted utilizing the ordinary bed.\n\nDiscussion:\nThese findings suggest a potential link between the ordinary bed and the colonists fatigue. The observed correlation between experiment frequency and fatigue intensity warrants further investigation.\n\nConsiderations:\nThe data aligns with previous observations regarding Subject's abnormal sleep on ordinary bed. Both instances deviate from the established rest protocols and suggest potential unforeseen consequences associated with standard sleep environments within the facility.\n\nRecommendations:\nGiven the potential detrimental effects, continued experimentation with the ordinary bed should be undertaken with caution. Further analysis of the ordinary bed's properties and its impact on colonists physiology is recommended.</text>
					</li>
					<li>
						<threshold>15</threshold>
						<label>#3/3 Ordinary bed study report</label>
						<text>Theory Regarding Ordinary Bed and Enhanced Cognitive Function\n\nSubject: {PAWN_nameDef}\n\nAbstract:\nThis report presents a novel theory proposed by Subject {PAWN_nameDef} regarding ordinary bed introduced into a research facility. Subject suggests the bed interacts with the brain neurons of nearby colonists, facilitating enhanced information processing capacity within the sleeper and leading to faster sleep recovery. This theory is based on data obtained during an anomalous sleep event involving Subject and ordinary bed. As a result of this event, the anomaly associated with the bed has been classified as Safe. Report concludes by outlining two primary options for moving forward: termination of the experiment by destruction of the ordinary bed, or continued use under controlled conditions for potential gain of research information.\n\nHypothesis:\nFollowing their non-standard sleep experience, {PAWN_nameDef} has proposed a theory concerning the ordinary bed. Subject suggest the bed utilizes the brain neurons of colonists in its vicinity. This interaction, according to {PAWN_nameDef}, facilitates increased information processing capacity within the sleeper.\n\nProposed Mechanism:\n{PAWN_nameDef}'s theory posits that by leveraging the colonists' collective neural network, the ordinary bed reduces the cognitive load on the sleeper's individual brain. This, in turn, would explain the observed rapid sleep recovery in Subject's case.\n\nOutcome:\nBased on information gleaned during this anomalous sleep event, {PAWN_nameDef} has successfully classified the anomaly associated with the ordinary bed as Safe.\n\nConsiderations:\nThe potential validity of Subject's theory requires further investigation. Additionally, a critical decision must be made regarding the ordinary bed.\n\nRecommendations:\nDestruction: Given the potential for unforeseen consequences related to the standard bed's influence on colonists' neural activity, its destruction may be the most prudent course of action.\nControlled Use: Alternatively, if Subject's theory regarding information processing holds merit, continued use of the standard bed, under controlled and monitored conditions, could offer significant advantages in anomaly research. This approach, however, necessitates thorough risk assessment and the development of safety protocols to safeguard colonists' well-being.</text>
					</li>
				</studyNotes>
			</li>
		</comps>
		<inspectorTabs>
			<li>ITab_StudyNotes</li>
		</inspectorTabs>
	</ThingDef>
	
</Defs>